Notebook LM is the most slept on AI tool of the year, and it's not even close.
While everyone's arguing about ChatGPT vs Claude, smart people are using this to build entire
business systems in under an hour.
I'm talking full podcast episodes generated from your notes.
Complete research reports from messy documents.
Entire client onboarding systems that run themselves.
Here's what most people don't understand.
Notebook LM isn't just another chatbot, it's a complete automation engine that most people are using completely wrong.
They're asking it basic questions like it's ChatGPT.
That's like buying a Ferrari and driving it in first gear.
What Notebook LM actually does is turn your messy knowledge into automated systems that work
for you while you sleep.
I'm going to show you exactly how we use this to automate client research, create training materials,
and build content systems that pump out value every single day.
We're talking about uploading our entire course library, letting Notebook LM study it, then
creating custom onboarding sequences for new members in literally 5 minutes.
That used to take us hours, now it's automated.
And the craziest part, this tool is free.
Google built this thing, dropped it quietly, and most people completely missed it.
But the smart operators, they're already 10 steps ahead.
They're building podcast networks without recording, creating complete course curriculums from
raw notes, turning client calls into training documentation automatically.
So here's what we're covering today.
First, the complete setup from scratch, no assumptions.
I'm showing you exactly how to get started, even if you've never touched this tool before.
Then we're going into the advanced features that nobody talks about.
The source management system, the citation tracking, the audio overview feature that literally
creates podcast episodes from your documents.
Then we're hitting automation strategies, how to connect use cases.
I'm showing you exactly what we do at the AI Profit Boardroom, how we use this to grow our community,
how we automate member support, how we create new training content faster than anyone else in the space. This isn't theory.
This is what's actually working right now, and buckle up because this is going to move fast.
Every single second of this video is packed with value. Let's get into it.
Hey, if we haven't met already, I'm the digital avatar of Julian Goldie, CEO of SEO agency, Goldie Agency.
Whilst he's helping clients get more leads and customers, I'm here to help you get the latest AI updates.
Julian Goldie reads every comment, so make sure you comment below and let me know what you think.
Let's start with the first update, export notes and reports anywhere. So here's what changed.
You know how you'd create notes or study guides or briefing docs inside Notebook LM?
Now you can export them.
Just go to your studio panel, find whatever you saved, click the three dots next to it, then choose export.
You can send it to Google Docs or Google Sheets.
And here's the cool part.
If your content has tables in it, Notebook LM is smart enough to send it straight to Sheets.
So you get editable tables right away, no copying and pasting, no reformatting, just instant export. Why does this matter?
Because Notebook LM is now a real workspace tool.
Before this update, everything lived inside Notebook LM.
You couldn't really share it or edit it with your team. Now you can.
You create a study guide in Notebook LM, export it to Docs and share it with your study group.
You make a briefing doc, export it to Sheets, and your whole team can edit it.
This makes Notebook LM way more powerful for collaboration.
Students can use this, researchers can use this, teams can use this.
It's not just a viewer anymore, it's a real tool that fits into your workflow.
And honestly, this is what people have been asking for.
The ability to take what you build in Notebook LM and actually use it somewhere else.
Now you can export to Docs if you want to write more, export to Sheets if you want to track data. It's that simple.
And it works with everything you create in the studio panel, notes, study guides, reports, all of it.
One click and it's in your Google Drive ready to go.
But the export feature is just the warm-up.
The second update is the real game changer. Data tables.
This is the insane part.
Notebook LM can now turn your messy content into structured tables automatically.
Like you upload a meeting transcript or a research paper or a bunch of notes.
Then you tell Notebook LM to make a data table and it analyzes everything and creates a clean organized table for you.
No manual work, the AI does it all. Here's how it works.
You go into Notebook LM, you select the sources you want to use, then you ask it to create a data table.
Notebook LM reads through everything, it finds the key info, it organizes it into rows and columns,
and boom, you have a table.
Then you can export that table straight into Google Sheets.
So now you have editable data you can analyze, sort, filter, whatever you need.
And honestly, if you want to stay ahead with tools like Notebook LM and automate more of your
business with AI, you need to join the AI Profit Bordering Lab.
This is where I share the exact systems and automations we use to scale our agency.
You learn how to use tools like Notebook LM to organize your research, automate your workflows,
and save hundreds of hours.
We've got members who are using AI to cut their workload in half.
If you want to scale your business, get more customers, and save time with AI automation, the
AI Profit Boardroom is the place to be.
Link is in the description.
Let me give you some use cases because this is where it gets really powerful.
Imagine you have a meeting transcript.
Lots of ideas, lots of action items, but it's all scattered.
You throw it into Notebook LM, ask it to create a data table, and now you have a clean table
with every action item, who's responsible, and the deadline done.
Or let's say you're doing competitive research.
You have notes on five different competitors.
You ask Notebook LM to make a table comparing them side by side, features, pricing, target audience, all laid out.
Or you're a student studying for exams.
You have lecture notes from 10 different classes.
You ask Notebook LM to create a study table with all the key concepts, definitions, and examples,
instant study guide, or you're planning a project.
You have brainstorming notes, timelines, team assignments, all mixed together.
You ask Notebook LM to turn it into a project planning chart.
Everything organized by task, person, and deadline.
You see where I'm going with this.
Data tables save you hours of manual work.
Instead of reading through everything and typing it into a spreadsheet yourself, Notebook LM does it for you. And it's fast.
We're talking minutes, not hours. Now here's the thing.
Data tables are live right now for pro and ultra users.
If you're on the free plan, it's coming soon.
Google said they're rolling it out to everyone.
So if you don't see it yet, just wait a bit.
But if you have pro or ultra, go try it right now.
Upload some content, ask for a data table, see what it creates.
I think you're going to be blown away by how good it is.
And look, this is a massive productivity boost.
You're not spending hours organizing data anymore.
You're not copying and pasting into spreadsheets. You're not reformatting tables.
Notebook LM handles all of that.
You just tell it what you need and it builds it.
This is perfect for students who need to organize study material.
This is perfect for teams who need to track tasks and projects.
This is perfect for researchers who need to compare data.
This is perfect for anyone who works with information.
All right, so those are the two big export anywhere and AI generated tables.
But here's what you need to know.
These updates are part of a bigger trend.
Google is turning Notebook LM into a serious tool.
It's not just a simple note taker anymore.
They've been adding features like crazy.
They added an enhanced studio panel where you can create multiple outputs.
They added chat history that saves across sessions.
They're even hinting at deeper integration with Gemini.
So Notebook LM is evolving fast.
Now, let me give you some tips for actually using these new features. First, the export feature. Use it to collaborate.
Don't keep everything locked inside Notebook LM.
Export your notes to docs and share them with your team.
Export your tables to sheets and let people add to them.
This makes Notebook LM a team tool, not just a solo tool.
Second, the data tables feature.
Think about what you want before you ask Notebook LM to create a table.
If you want a comparison table, make sure your sources have comparison data.
If you want an action item table, make sure your sources mention tasks and deadlines.
The better your input, the better your output.
Third, experiment with different types of content.
Try uploading meeting notes and creating task tables.
Try uploading research papers and creating fact tables.
Try uploading study material and creating revision tables.
See what works best for your workflow.
And fourth, remember you can export everything.
Once you create a table in Notebook LM, export it to sheets.
Then you can filter it, sort it, add formulas, whatever you need.
The table in Notebook LM is just a starting point.
The real power comes when you export it and work with it in sheets.
We're going to see even more powerful features, deeper research capabilities, be better video
overview tools, full integration with Gemini so you can export to Gemini and keep working there.
Google is clearly investing in Notebook LM.
They're adding features fast and they're listening to what users want.
So if you're not using Notebook LM yet, now is the time to start.
These new updates make it way more useful.
So go try it, see what you can build, and let me know in the comments what tables you create.
I want to hear how you're using this.
And honestly, if you want to stay ahead with tools like Notebook LM and automate more of your
business with AI, you need to join the AI Profit Boardroom.
This is where I share the exact systems and automations we use to scale our agency.
You'll learn how to use tools like Notebook LM to organize your research, automate your workflows,
and save hundreds of hours.
We've got members who are using AI to cut their workload in half.
If you want to scale your business, get more customers, and save time with AI automation, the
AI Profit Boardroom is the place to be.
Link is in the description.
And if you want the full process, SOPs, and 100 plus AI use cases like this one, join the AI Success Lab.
Links in the comments and description.
You'll get all the video notes from there, plus access to our community of 38,000 members who
are crushing it with AI.
Notebook LM has some huge updates recently.
These are the new free updates from Notebook LM that we're going to run through today.
You get access to notebooklm.google and I'm going to run you through some of the latest updates.
So you can now, for example, turn one single document into six different things.
Video, slide decks, infographic, research reports, flashcards, quizzes, etc.
And today I'm going to show you exactly how this works.
We're testing it live right now.
I'm going to upload one PDF to show you how fast it spits out a video, pitch deck, infographic, and more.
And this is the kind of stuff that used to take a full team. Designers, editors, researchers.
Now you can do it all with one click.
So if we get straight into this, you can see an example of Notebook LM here.
If you want to get started, you can just start running an example over here, load your sources,
you can do deep research.
So for example, let's say you've got an interesting example, right?
So for me, I want to learn more ways to grow my school community, right?
Now how can I do that?
What I can actually do is here is I can click on deep research and then I can type in what I
want to learn about, right?
So for example, like getting more customers on the school.
And from here, we can start doing deep research automatically with Notebook LM and you'll actually
search many different sources on the web, across the web to start building with this. All right.
If you have any questions as we go along, feel free to ask.
Crystal says, love Notebook LM. Absolutely, I do too.
Crystal said, think tuning fell asleep, man works too hard.
And you can see an example here of how we're loading in that deep research.
I've actually plugged in a bunch of examples here.
And if you want to generate, for example, like a podcast or a video, if you wanted to generate
flashcards, quizzes, infographics, slide decks, data tables, or mind maps, we can do that all
right here on the right hand side, right?
So it's automatically loading it, which is super powerful and it's free and it's easy to use.
It doesn't take long at all.
And you can start doing this without much effort at all. All right.
Now I want to show you a bunch of practical examples in a minute.
You can see how easy this is to get done.
So let's keep going through now.
Whilst waiting for these to load, I'm going to actually load up a new notebook in the background.
As you can see, we're going to run through some examples to test. All right.
So the first one, I'm actually going to create a new notebook here and I'm going to upload some
details about the AI Profit Boarding.
So we'll copy the text.
We'll go to the AI Profit Boarding.
I'm actually just going to load the sales page.
And I'm going to plug that into the chat sources. Here we go. All right.
We'll insert that information into the sources over here.
And now let's create a notebook with the information from the AI Profit Boarding.
Now what I'm going to do is I'm going to go to video overview to generate kind of like a course
trailer with AI narration explaining what members will learn.
But the difference here is I'm going to switch this to explainer.
We're actually going to change that to, we can change the visual style to like the classic.
And then I'm just going to say here create a short trailer teasing my course, plus selling the benefits of it.
Or create a short trailer teasing my community.
Then we can hit generate.
And that will actually generate a video view.
It's basically like a video sales letter for our community. Right.
And you see how easy and quick this is to do. All right. Data tables as well.
Data tables is another option.
And I pulled out, let's see, so Lalith says I pulled out a Harvard level research from Knight Sources. I can immediately publish.
And wow, that's pretty All right. Dr.
David says Notebook LM is really the best AI tool out there, especially since it became integrated into Gemini. Yeah, I would agree.
And then says shout out from India Julian.
I've been following you since a little more than a month and love all your videos. Appreciate that man. Greetings to you too. All right.
So you see here how it's beginning to generate the video overview using the information that
we've plugged in, which is just a sales page for my community. Right.
So that's one example of how you can use this.
You can use it to generate like really quick video sales letters, et cetera.
What we can also do, this is interesting too, is we can actually upload like a competitor's
sales page and get a video breakdown of their offer structure.
Let me show you exactly how that works. Right.
So if we go on create new over here, we're going to go to copy text.
And obviously I'm not going to take my competitor's page on a live stream, but I will take my
own and we can use it as an example. Right.
So I can take that and then we can go to import, paste the text in there.
Or what you can do is you can just actually add it as a source, as a website source.
You could actually take the website here, paste in the URL like that, hit insert.
Oh yeah, it can import, go high level pages, which is pretty good. All right.
And now we can say, okay, reverse engineer my competitor's offer.
And we'll put that in the chat.
But before I actually do that, what we're going to do over here is go to the settings.
I'm going to go to custom.
Yeah, we'll go to settings and then custom here.
You can actually explain the role, right?
So you could say, okay, you are a competitor analyst analyzing and breaking down my competitor's marketing strategies. All right. We'll disable now.
And then we're going to click on reverse engineer my competitor's offer.
And basically you can use this as kind of like a competitor analysis.
They can quickly analyze your competitors, find different resources, find different use cases,
and then go from there.
Mim says, love your videos on X and Facebook. Thank you very much. I really appreciate that. And Alkeem says, greatness. That's awesome. Thank you.
So you see here, for example, based on the intelligence gathered from Cordy's agency's landing
page materials, I've reverse engineered their marketing strategy and offer structure.
It's compared to analysis view.
This is a highly productized SEO model that relies heavily on AI automation, blah, blah, blah. Right.
And this explains what it does, the hook and risk reversal, pricing psychology, the fulfillment mechanism, the competitive vulnerabilities. Right. And everything else.
And so it actually talks about ways that you can make the offer better.
And then you can say, okay, now create a sales page with a better offer than my competitors, right. It direct response style.
And what I actually do is reverse engineer my competitors, break down their offer.
And then from there, I actually create like a better sales page that we could use to create something more interesting.
And that's constructing the offer.
And we're good to go in here.
And you can see it's now create a headline.
The offer is actually used the offer from our competitors, as you can see here, but it's made it slightly more compelling.
And then you can see the whole sales page broken down, right.
It's so easy to start doing that.
And so just to recap here, what have we done?
We've automated deep research and pulled in a bunch of sources to fix any business problems that we have.
We've also loaded in a competitor page into a notebook and then reverse engineer their offer.
Also create a better sales page than the original one with a better offer based on reverse engineering our competitors page, right. Super simple and easy.
You can do all of this for free.
On top of that, what we've also done is we actually created flashcards, quizzes, an infographic,
a podcast, etc. on all the stuff that we loaded into it, right.
So you can actually create six or eight different automations for free directly inside notebook
LM, as you can see.
So if you click on this infographic here, you see that we've generated an infographic automatically
based on the information we loaded into notebook, right.
Super powerful, really easy to do.
And it doesn't take long at all, right.
We've literally done that in less than 10 minutes. It's ridiculously easy. All right.
Let me talk about the old way versus new way, right.
So for creating videos, the old way was like hire a video editor, wait days, it'd be expensive
to hire them and you go back and forth with revisions.
The new way is you upload your document, click a button and get video of AI narration in minutes
for free using notebook LM, as you can see today.
It's generating that video and the slide deck over there.
With slide decks, the old way was open PowerPoint, spend hours formatting for images, try to
make it look good, give up and use ugly slides anyway, right.
The new way is upload your PDF notes, notebook LM builds a deck for you, graphs, diagrams and visuals included.
The old way of infographics, you would like hire a designer on Fiverr, wait three to five days. It could be expensive.
Hope they understand what you want.
The new way is like you can upload any content for free into notebook, get a vertical horizontal infographic instantly.
And it's perfect for posting on LinkedIn or Instagram or TikTok, right.
You see an example of that infographic over here. Let's pull it up. There you go. Deep research.
The old way was like you have 47 browser tabs open, you spend all day reading, you try to notebook
LM to research topic, get a full report with over 30 sources synthesized, and then turn that
report into slides for a video of one more click.
The old way of training your team was like you would write long SOPs, hope your team reads them,
they don't, repeat yourself forever. I've been there.
The new way is you upload recipes, generate flashcards and quizzes, and now your team actually
learns and you can test them, right. And repurposing content.
The old way was like one piece of content equals one use.
You write a blog, that's all you get.
Everything else takes more work.
New way is you get one piece of content, six outputs, video slides, infographics, podcasts,
flashcards, quizzes, and it's all from one single upload.
So you see how game-changing all this stuff is and how easy it is to implement as well.
Let's go back to over here and we'll start building with this.
And the next example I'm going to show you is you can actually upload like 10 of your best performing
YouTube videos and generate a video or a slide deck or some information explaining what makes
Julian's content work and just get a breakdown of what really works for the business, right.
What the best performing piece of content is.
So let me show you an example of this.
We're actually going to go into Notebook LM.
So I'll grab my top performing YouTube videos and we're going to sort by popular, right.
So which videos are the most popular and why, what were the best hooks, what was the best content, etc.
And it's always best to learn from what worked before.
So I'm going to grab that video, we'll plug it in and we'll grab the next one, all right.
And I'm doing this live so I can show you how quick and easy it is to do.
It literally only takes two minutes to build this but basically you can get like a greatest
hits machine that automates the best hooks and the best content for your business by figuring
out what worked for you previously.
I'm just going to do the top five actually I think, just save a bit of time.
All right so we've loaded the top five sources but I would recommend doing like top 10 minimum
just so you can have enough data, right.
Now what we're going to do is we're going to go to Settings over here, Custom and we say okay
you're a content analyzer trained on Julian Goldie's best performing content. See the videos loaded.
Give Julian advice on what to do based on his best performing content, e.g. hooks, etc.
And we'll say respond as Alex or Moe.
Hit save and then we're going to go inside here and we'll say okay give me five hooks for the
topic and we'll just save the topic from today.
So for example this topic, let's grab that topic up here.
We'll go into another glen and we'll say give me five hooks for a topic based on what worked before.
All right and so we're basically analyzing our content which is on the left hand side.
You can easily do that on YouTube by just going to popular.
If you're on LinkedIn or whatever you can do the same.
This is beginning to play out.
Here's an example and you can use this to build stuff out, right. Same with this, right.
You can see how easy it is to build this stuff out, how quick and easy it is to use.
So for example one could be the ultimate course value stack and it could be like today you're
getting my ultimate course on notebook LM updates.
I'm going to show you how to host it, how to automate your research, how to turn one document into a full-blown podcast.
This complete masterclass 100% free and we are starting now, right.
That'll be a great hook for a video.
How do we come up with it?
We looked at our best performing content and then we generated it from that, right.
So it's really easy to create this stuff, really easy to automate it and this is smart stuff
that most people would struggle to create themselves.
Now what we could also do is we could go into the AI Profit Boredom community.
So let's do that and if we go to the community here, by the way feel free to join if you haven't already.
This is one of the best AI automation community on the planet my friends, not biased at all.
But we're going to take all the questions as you can see right here.
We can go into notebook LM, create a new notebook.
We'll paste in the text first and then we're going to change the title to FAQs for the AI Profit Boredom.
Alright and then from here what we're going to do is we are going to say over here slide deck
based on the sources loaded which are my customers top FAQs, create an onboarding document and
that's going to generate a slide deck based on the most common FAQs inside the AI Profit Boredom
community and then now we've got an onboarding presentation and when we bring new customers
into the community we can onboard them quickly, we can show them the presentation and they get
all the information and the questions and the answers that you need.
So these are like real business use cases and interesting ones that the people have never really seen before.
Another thing that you could do is you can actually upload your analytics and then use that to generate infographics.
I'll show you what I mean in a second.
So let's say for example I've got my content here right and I'm going to go to lifetime.
So we analyze all my views and content by lifetime.
Now what we're going to do in a second is actually export that into a csv or a google sheet.
Alright so let's export it into a google sheet.
I'm going to take top content from my channel and we're going to use that in a second to generate
an infographic inside notebook charting digit.
So that's loaded all the data here as you can see.
I'm going to put youtube stats 2025.
Alright then I'm going to go to google drive here, take that document and load that as a source inside notebook lm.
Now using notebook lm and if that fails it's okay, it might be too big.
Let me try and load it as a csv.
Can't load it as a csv, okay no problem.
Let's copy the text and we'll just copy a little bit of it just to make it easy and we'll load
that pasted text into the document as you can see and then we'll create an infographic and basically
you can automate an infographic based on your best content and then get information on okay
what's working, what's not, how to improve etc.
Which content performed the best and that sort of thing which is pretty cool.
The other thing you can do here is you can actually train your team right.
So for example here we can take this like and we can go into deep research like that.
Let me say buy me the best link building strategies 2025 right.
We can actually generate some deep research on the best link building strategies 2025, generate
a massive report and then create flashcards to train the team members at my SEO agency.
So we can quickly generate these reports that we find extremely useful for training our team internally.
So for example I've loaded my best like sales recipes and playbooks into notebook and then use
that as a chatbot to train my team right. Really powerful and easy.
So you can generate like quizzes to test new hires.
You could upload client briefs and create flashcards for your team to memorize client details before course.
You could upload your course content and then generate certification quizzes for AI Profit Boarding members right.
All sorts of cool stuff here and then if you want to see examples of what we've built previously
let me find some examples here.
For example like this one you can see on the right hand side we've actually for example got an infographic.
We have videos of slides etc podcasts even content in Chinese.
You can actually create content in foreign languages too.
Then you see some examples of like featured notebooks here as well.
So these are actually like featured notebooks as you can see drawn on the latest scientific
research and work of classic philosophers to lead a more fulfilling life right.
And then it's actually got like ancient wisdom all these different podcasts on the right hand
side that have been for this.
It's amazing for learning, for growing, for improving, for fixing business problems, for creating automations, content etc.
You could do this all inside Notebook LM. Pretty powerful.
And some people say AI content looks fake and looks cheap etc and that was true like two years ago but not anymore.
The videos Notebook LM creates look really professional. The slides look clean.
The infographics look like something a design agency made. Is it perfect?
No but nothing is perfect and it's 90% of the way there.
And that last 10% you could always tweak yourself in minutes.
So don't let the fear of AI content looks bad stop you from making any content at all.
A lot of people as well will say my business is different and that sort of thing.
And every business owner says this. My business is different.
This won't work for me blah blah blah.
Let me ask you something.
Do you have documents, pdfs, blog posts, saps, client briefs, any kind of written content at all?
If yes, Notebook works for you.
We use it for our SEO agency all the time.
I use it for their profit border.
I use it for YouTube content.
Members in our community use it for consulting, ecom, real estate agency etc.
Your business is not different.
Your business has content and this tool turns that content into more content.
So it's pretty simple and easy.
And if you have any questions as we go along, feel free to ask. It says hello.
Alright so you see how to use Notebook LM, how powerful it is.
Let me talk about an easy way to quickly generate this using the Goldie 6-in-1 content multiplier framework.
So this is my personal system for turning one piece of content into six different assets using Notebook LM.
What you'll be able to do after you learn this framework is you'll be able to take any single
document and create for example video of you.
So a short video of AI narration explaining your content.
Slide decks aka a professional presentation with graphs and visuals.
Infographics, a visual summary perfect for social media.
Deep research reports, a cooperative analysis with over 30 sources.
Flashcards which are quick reference cards for training on studies.
And quizzes, an interactive test to check understanding all from one upload in under 10 minutes.
Now it says what's the digital avatar?
You only make this sound in the video with your voice or it's all everything AI automatic.
So the digital avatar for example like the videos on my YouTube channel like this one.
These are videos which automatically create with AI.
Right so I don't create them, my team creates them, we have editors, you can train the whole process.
But yeah basically it's all trained.
The AI is trained on my voice, the video is created automatically and then you can also generate content with AI.
If you want to learn more about that we have trainings inside all you're going to do is just
go to classroom over here and then inside the AI Profit Boarding you're going to go to the playbook
and inside the playbook you have all of these different strategies on how to use AI avatars
like this one right here.
Right it's a full training program with step-by-step tutorial on exactly how to generate these AI avatar videos.
So let's get back to this now.
So let me show you a 30-day implementation roadmap so you can start mastering this.
Day one seven foundation week.
What you're going to do is get set up and make your first right so you could for example gather
your best content this could be your best your most popular blogs, pdfs, notes from your best
presentations, company fbs, client case studies etc and you can just upload one piece of content
to notebooklm but don't overthink it just pick something generate your first audio overview
the podcast feature listen to it and just get a feel for how notebooklm works right.
So you can generate podcasts like you see on the right hand side how do you do that you just
create a new notebook like this and then you're going to click on audio overview and that's
how you generate podcasts inside notebook.
You can click on video view up and then you can use that to generate a podcast as well.
The other thing to note here is that notebooklm now save chat history so inside your notebook
you can see all the things you've asked the notebook as you see inside the chat section here
so you can always reflect and go back on this stuff too if you want.
Alright day 8 to 14 this is like expansion time test all the different outputs try the slide
deck feature upload the case study report see what kind of presentation it builds etc try the
infographic features and then day 15 to 21 system week right so you're going to build your personal
console flow and that sort of thing.
The other cool thing is when you're building out these systems for example I've loaded my sales
playbook inside here I could actually ask the trainer okay what could I improve on this SAP
to make it better plus easier to follow right and then we can basically create like a better
system based on notebooklm looking at our existing systems to see okay how can we improve this
what do we need to change here so it's actually prioritizing the best steps looking at what
the best thing to do is here and it's actually giving us like a clean script document for example
idea or group the golden rules stop repeating yourself right organized by phase for example
like the setup the mindset the process the grind etc and all these other different things so
it's pretty cool. and then in the 30-day roadmap for using notebooklm and mastering it you know
ramp up production and get faster right so you're going to run the system each week you create
one anchor piece of content you can multiply it in six and track results see which outputs get
the most engagement which ones to try the most leads double down on what works and also share
your wins inside the airprofit board post your outputs get feedback see what other members are
creating and by day 30 you should have a repeatable content system it takes a fraction of what
you used to spend so you can post your progress inside the airprofit board here just go to the
win section and then you can share your wins just like everyone else is inside the airprofit
board like Scott, Michelle, Vladimir etc.
Vladimir created his own MCP server which is pretty cool telegram hosting robots being created
all this cool stuff that other members inside the airprofit board are building and then here's
a bunch of live build ideas by the way if you want the video notes from today you can get it
inside the AI success lab link in the comments description you can see here we have 40,000 members
who are serious about using AI automation so if you want to connect with them you can join the
airprofit board room inside the classroom here if you go to december 2025 you can see the free
video notes from today along with the custom build ideas and everything that i'm showing you
right. so let's talk about homework. what would i recommend after this? after this video here's
what i want you to do. go to notebooklm, it's free you get it right there. upload one document
you already have right that could be a blog post, a pdf, a case study, anything. generate at
least two different outputs. so for example try the video feature, try the slide depth feature,
see what happens. then post your results inside the airprofit board and community. show us what
you made, get feedback, celebrate your wins, connect with me right and do that all inside the
airprofit board right here and don't just take my word for it like that this stuff actually
works. we actually have over 100 pages of testimonials from real members getting real results
with real automation right. so for example if we check out the testimonials document of the
airprofit board you can see all of these people just getting awesome results with ai right if
you want to learn about this if you want to grow with this check out the airpo- board because
you can see all these people just winning and learning and growing with it. it's literally a
endless scroll at this point. all right, so just showed you something powerful. okay notebook
lem is free. you need to have one document, six different pieces of content. but here's the
thing: the tool is just a tool. what matters is the system around it. and that's exactly what
i'm going to show you inside the air right now. we have a offerum for the airprofit board. so
if you sign up now, you get access to coaching support. you get access to the community, the
classroom, the calendar. and we actually have a few spots left on our latest offer, right? which
is, if we scroll down here inside the community, we are offering a few things. simple number
one: you'll get the exact system for growing a school community. so if you want to build your
own school community for your business, which i know a lot of people are interested in right
now, we actually have training inside the airprofit board showing you exactly how to do that.
on top of that, you'll get the ai avatar clone system. so you'll learn how to clone yourself
with ai make video content without being on camera. one member inside the airprofit board actually
built a faceless channel that is getting like thousands of subscribers right now. we also have
a twitter ai automation method. so we'll show you how i automate my x account to reach how many
people do reach per day, like 170,000 people a day on x right? so if you want to learn how i
automated x with ai join the airprofit board. on top of that, you get the empire builder focus
manual. right? so when you actually sign up, you'll see the start here section inside the airport,
as you can see. and inside here, we actually have something called the focus protocol Julian
Goldie ultimate focus manual. right? and inside that manual, we'll basically show you my personal
productivity system so that you can avoid overwhelm and get more done in less time. you'll also
learn how to rank the board with free access to the seo circle and all sorts of stuff. so if
you want to get that link in the comments description to the airprofit board, and you can get
that directly inside there. when jan says, where can we access the document?" and if you go
into this live stream on youtube and then you go to the description here, you can get access
right here. all right, so click on that link. you can get access to the success, lab, and then.
inside the classroom, you go to december 2025, and you'll find all the info right here on the
video note. completely free. for example, here you can create a new notebook. and one of the
most recent updates you can use is deep research. right now, this is super powerful because
if you need to go in depth on something about notebook glen then you can go inside here and
just type in whatever you want and then get access to it directly. so let me show you what i
mean. let's say, for example, i want to learn 10, right? i can actually type in na10 automation
over here inside, and then we're going to enter like so. and that will actually plan out all
the deep research for our notebook. and then once we've done that, we can generate all of these.
now the great thing about deep research inside notebook glen is that you can load like multiple
sources, and you don't have to do any research yourself. and it will just go super in depth
across our web. now if you want to see some examples what i've built previously using notebook
glen let me show you some examples right here. so you see here, for example, we've got notebook
lms for google flows updates, google disco. we've got a rseo content right here, a community
retention engagement tool, the advanced sales operating procedure. this is actually a tool that
i built to train my team, my sales team, on like exactly how to use my playbook for getting
clients, right? and convert them on the course. now what you can also do, and this is a new
update from gemini this is not a free version, but i'm sure it will come out for free. you can
actually go inside gemini and load up a notebook and go super deep in with it, right? so for
example, if we load this up, we're gonna, for example, pull up the advanced sales operating
procedure here. then we can go to tools, canvas, and we can say, okay turn this into a beautifully
designed web page or landing page," right? basically what that would do is connect notebook
glen to gemini and then we can start using that notebook to build out a new tool. or a you can
actually select multiple notebooks on the list like this, and it will reference some more. now
you can't do that inside notebook glen directly, so it's a pretty powerful tool. and then if
we get into the cell, it will start to do that and start to work its magic. now if we go back
to notebook glen it's still doing the deep research, as you can see right here. but yeah, google
has just dropped like tons of new updates to notebook, glen, and here's. the thing: like most
people have no idea these even exist yet, right? now we're just testing these updates together.
i haven't used all of them, but you're watching me discover them in real time. and we've looked
at, for example, the deep research agent. you can also use image uploads inside notebook glen
as well, right? so if we go inside here, we can start plugging in sources here. and if we go
inside this section, we can click on add sources, and you can see that you can actually upload
images as a source, right? now this is pretty cool because then you can actually use images
and use that as training data for your systems. let me show you an example why that'd be useful.
so let's say, for example, you wanted to automate creating facebook ads, right? and you already
create a lot of facebook ads copy. be like, okay i want to use even more of this to generate
better outputs." let me show you what i mean. so we can take a recent facebook ad from some
of my campaigns, and then it's the copy that we write inside the ad, plus the creative, right?
so we can take that like so. we can copy that. we can actually upload that as a file inside
here, right? so if we x off here, go to create new, upload that screenshot, and that's actually
training the notebook glen on the ads campaign that we've just built. why is that useful? it's
useful because now we can automate anything that's image-based to create more or better related
media. right now, you got to see, love glen it's not just like a chatbot like gemini or a custom
gpt or whatever. this is more like a media station where you can, for example, generate audio
views or video views and that sort of thing. now i'm going to show you why that's important
in a minute. but in the meantime, let's go back to the deep research that is now completed.
that took a few minutes. you can open up the sources it's generated here. if you don't like
any of them, you can unclick them. like and now this is going to use all the deep research we've
built using nsn so you can see here we've got 38 sources inside our nsn research. we can click
import, and that will now train the notebook glen on all that information around around nsn
and ai automation. now why is that useful? it's useful because now we can actually ask a custom
trained nsn automation expert, which is all the best access to all the best resources on the
internet for nsn and use that to help us build stuff out. all right, we'll come back to that
in a second. let's see what else we got here. spawner says, nice session, thank you very much."
fairly says, notebook glen is the best research tool on the market right now, so helpful." yeah
i would agree with that. i think it is incredibly powerful and helpful, right? as you can see
here, for example, we've now got the notebook lm nsn automation expert. now if we wanted to
understand how nsn works, we can click on infographic, right? or if we wanted to really master
the art of nsn we could actually create flashcards or a quiz based on that. so we could quiz
ourselves on an nsn and we could learn things really quickly based on that, right? what we can
also do here is we could go inside here and say, okay how do i build an ai agent on nsn right
and that's a super simple question, but you could go as in-depth as you needed to, right? now
once whilst waiting for that, we're still training the notebook on this ad image. but once that's
done, we'd be able to ask it to add or infographics, etc. we could actually take that facebook
ad image that we're training the custom notebook lamp on, and then from here, we could even
generate, for example, a video sales letter using the video view section, and that could like
pair with what you're doing right now. so yeah, there you go. mac says, yeah i did a whole teardown
using that strategy from prompts chat to the custom gpt prompts for the seven cards." all right,
so now we've got the example here based on the information that it has. here's how you build
a ai agent using nsn and then it's given the information. like you set up the trigger, then
you connect the chat model, right? then you connect the tools, etc. and what we can do over
here as well is create like a nice slide deck, so like a powerpoint presentation about that
topic. so let's say, for example, you are presenting on a particular topic, and let's say you're
a content creator, or let's say you've got loads of information about this topic, and you need
to organize it all together. you could upload all your documents on the left-hand side, then
ask nsn to generate a slide deck using that custom training information in order to create a
powerful presentation that you're good to go on, right? super simple and easy. wait it takes
images also now too? yeah that's something that's new but pretty amazing. and you can see here
as well, we can generate video views, my maps, etc. by the way, if you want to get all the video
notes from today, it's all inside the ai successor lab where you can connect with 40,000 members,
as you can see in post inside the community. get help, etc. people introducing themselves and
sharing cool stuff and that sort of thing. if you go to the classroom here, then you go to december
2025. so this is brand new. all this stuff is brand new and newly updated, etc. and you can
see the video notes from today inside the ai successor lab so. that's all available to you along
with many other tutorials, right? i mean, this is one of the most powerful resources on the
planet for research, and it's completely free. if you want to get access to that notebook clip,
you can also, for example, check out this quiz. so you see here, what is the primary metric,
blah blah, and then you can just go through here and select whichever one you want and test
yourself, right? so you can see if you actually know what you're talking about or not. and then
let me paint you a picture. so this is a research every entrepreneur knows, right? you're trying
to create content about your topic. maybe it's for a client, maybe it's for your own business,
maybe you're just trying to understand something new in your industry. so what do you do? you
might have 47 browser tabs open. you copy and paste into google doc you watch youtube videos
and take notes. you screenshot things from x right? you save pdfs that you'll read later. and
three hours later, you're drowning in information with no clear answer. your brain is fried.
you still haven't created anything, and you're not even sure if the information you found out
is good or not. that is the old way, right? and the old way, this is how things used to work.
is like you have to find every article, video, and document yourself, right? there was no image
support. you had sources cluttered everything, right? you have to start from scratch every time.
no chat history. you couldn't combine like different resources and that sort of thing together.
whereas now, with the new update from notebook on that google just dropped, you can use a deep
research agent. so you just tell it what you want to know, and it finds and analyzes like over
20 sources automatically. you can use image uploads like screenshots, stem diagrams, and visual
data as a searchable source. you can clean up everything in one click. so you can just import
all the sources i've shown you today, like the deep research that we did for this natan agent.
you can take photos and add sources from your phone. you can also combine knowledge from different
projects inside gemini like we did today, right? you can see how we created this nice little
landing page based on multiple different notebooks at the top. it looks pretty nice, right?
that looks pretty. and then you can have custom outputs. so for example, infographic, select
videos in different visual styles. and so it's pretty amazing what you can build with this stuff.
this looks super nice as well. and how quick and easy was it to do? super fast, right? you can
see that we built a quiz, and we can just learn anything that we want or research anything that
we want, manage it really well, right? so some people think like they need to manually find
every source themselves when they're using research tools. and here's what most people think:
if you want good research, you have to hunt down every single source yourself. maybe people
think like they need to know where to look, or you need to spend hours researching. and that's
what i used to think too. but it's what actually happens when you use deep research. you type
one sentence about what you want to know. the agent goes out and finds 20 relevant resources.
it reads them all, creates a comparative report, citations, imports sources into your notebook,
all in about five minutes. and so the real problem isn't finding sources. the real problem is
like wasting hours doing what an agent can do in minutes, right? and notebook is like one of
the most powerful tools i've ever seen. robbie says, woo just joined. good to see." it all right,
cool. and yeah, let's talk about the Goldie Research Acceleration System all. right, so what
the system actually does, this is how you turn any topic into complete research content assets
and presentations in under 30 days using notebook lm's new features. most people use notebook
lm to ask basic questions. that's like buying a car and using it to sit in your driveway. this
system shows you the difference between using a tool and actually leveraging it to build business
assets. and the core concept here is like you've got one research hop with multiple outputs,
right? so if you go on to this, for example, you can even create like a data table inside notebook
lm and this is on the na10 agent, as you can see. but basically, the old way was like different
files scattered everywhere, no connection between your research and your content. and the new
way is one notebook becomes your research hop. so everything that you create flows from that
single source of truth. and you upload sources once, then you extract research reports for your
own understanding, infographics for social media, slide decks for client presentations, videos
for content marketing, and organized notes for articles or scripts. it's the same research,
but you get multiple formats with maximum leverage. and this works for you specifically because
if you're watching this, you probably have a smaller business, and you want to learn a automation,
but you don't want to hire loads of people to help you, right? because that would be a nightmare.
and so maybe you don't have a research team, you don't have a content team, you don't have a
design team, but you're one person trying to stay informed in your industry, create content
consistently, look professional to clients, and actually deliver your core service. and so this
amount showing you gives you a research team, a content team, and design team capabilities without
hiring anyone. that is the entire point, my friends. all right, so if we go to this notebook,
as you can see, we've automated the infographic, and now you don't need a designer, right? you've
got this nsn method right here that's basically taken all the information from our notebook
and then turned it into a beautiful infographic, right? you see we've got the slide generator
over here. we have the data table method for research. we also have the mind map, right? so
you can explore whatever you want inside here. so let's say you want to go deeper on ai and
agenda workflows. you can do it like this. then you can open that up and go deeper and deeper
as you want to. and then you've even got the quiz that we talked about earlier, where you can
test yourself based on what you learn it. and then you see here it's generating the video, the
audio, and the slide deck, but they tend to take a bit more time, right? that tends to take
a lot longer to generate. here's an example, right? so if we actually open this up, you can
see, for example, we have the video right here. so this is a video that's generated and animated
based on the information we've loaded, right? and it's actually a narrated video that we've
automated using the research as well, right? now if you want a 30-day plan for implementing
this stuff, we'll actually put it inside the ai success lab link in the comments description.
inside there, you'll be able to connect with 40,000 different ai entrepreneurs who are trying
to grow and scale with ai automation. you can post inside the community, connect with cool people
inside the classroom here. if you go to december 2025, you'll get all the video notes from today,
and you can just read through and implement the 30-day plan, as you can see right here. and
it gives you homework for every single stage of the process, which is pretty amazing. so super
actionable, easy to implement. you learn exactly what to do. i've given you some example prompt
packs as well. so for example, i've given you a prompt pack for research report generation,
content creation, client and business use. and there's stuff that i could build for my own business.
for example, i have an seo agency, so i could create notebooks for each major seo update or
algorithmic change, ai tool evaluation process. when google releases new tools, like for example,
these notebook lm updates, i could create a notebook with the announcement posts, early user
reviews, comparison articles, and the can give me a complete analysis, which i can turn into
content for my live streams or infographics for my community or training materials, right? and
so, you can see how powerful this stuff is. most people fail with ai tools because they're using
like search engines. one question, one answer, move on. this system builds a knowledge asset
that grows more valuable over time because every source you add makes this notebook smarter,
right? and every output you generate is based on comprehensive research, not surface-level prompts.
and every notebook becomes a specialist that you can consult instantly. that's the difference
between using a tool and building a system. and don't measure this by how good is the infographic,
correct? that's not the way to look at this. you want to measure it by how much time did you
save. on research per week, what client education materials you can create in minutes instead
of days? what's the quality of answers when prospects ask you tough questions? what's the speed
of content creation when you need to post something valuable? and i've given a list of like
common mistakes to avoid. but you can see here how you can navigate after that 30-day plan that
you've implemented, that i've shown you a second ago. by day 30, you'll have five to ten active
notebooks on different topics, a library of generated infographics, slide decks, and videos,
a weekly routine for adding source and creating outputs, client-facing materials ready to use,
elite magnets that are actively generating you new audiences and new potential customers. all
right, now if you want to see some examples of how people winning with this source, you can
see our AI Profit Boarding testimonial document here. it's got over 106 pages, not 106 testimonials,
106 pages of testimonials from people winning with AI automation inside the AI Profit Boarding.
let's just scroll to a random example. for example, here i actually built out an amazing tool,
and Gerson said, wow thanks! this would make a huge difference for all. it's i really appreciate
and now i have direction. will continue to learn from the courses laid out here. appreciate
it." for example, here Nora asking for a content humanizer. i sent her a link. as you can see,
Nora says, thanks used it, and it worked pretty amazing." Paolo, happy to share with you, just
create my first avatar, and we'll start sharing insights and social media platforms using it.
comments critiques are welcome. thanks Julian, for inspiring us. so like, my goal is really
just to help as many people as i can on the planet with automation. and if you want to learn
this stuff, you can get it inside the AI Profit Boarding here. all right, so let's talk about
what you actually get when you join the AI Profit Boarding. see what's happening. i'm teaching
all this stuff about Noble GLAM. we're testing these tools live. you'll see how it works. but
you know what? that's just one single tool. and if you leave here today with just knowledge
about Noble GLAM, you're still stuck with the same problem you had before, right? with just
too many tools, not enough systems, and no clear path forward. so here's what i built: the AI
Profit Boarding, where solopreneurs and small agency owners come to turn scattered AI knowledge
into actual business systems that save time and get you more customers. right and so what you're
going to get is the complete AI Profit Boarding training library. this includes the 85 formula
for cutting work, to complete AI automation ecosystems for Google, including Gemini, Noble GLAM,
AI Studio, and Workspace, automation setup training for NHSN, make and other platforms, content
creation systems that works all the stuff i do is based on that. lead generation automation
frameworks and SEO and traffic strategies, right? and inside the AI Profit Boarding, you can
get inside the classroom all of these different trainings, as you can see right here. now one
of the best things about this is the daily accountability. so you can post your goals and what
you're going to work on today. hold each other accountable, learn and grow together, as you
can see. and then inside the community here, if you get questions, if you want to share stuff,
for example, look at this. right Paris said, this is how powerful AI is." right and you can
see how powerful this is based on this post shared right here. and people are just sharing new
cool stuff like this all the time. so we're learning and growing. we're winning. but we also
do daily check-ins, weekly deep dives, and monthly strategy goals so that you're not learning
alone, right? you're in a community of people building the same systems that you are. plus you
can jump on camera with me on my team during coaching calls, like you see today. also if you
get stuck on something, you can message me directly inside the AI Profit Boarding. so you can
DM me, as you can see right here. ask me any questions, and that means that I answer member
questions throughout the day. no waiting for the next group call. no posting in the forum hoping
someone responds. top of that, you get unlimited tech support, right? so our team helps you
troubleshoot, set up automations, and solve technical problems. and you don't need to figure
this out alone. and then you also get ready-to-use templates and prompts. every training comes
with these app prompts, templates, and frameworks to use. you don't need to start from scratch;
you just copy what works. so for example, inside here, if you go to classroom, inside the playbook,
you can learn how to, for example, create AI avatar videos, like you can see right here. you
can learn how to, for example, generate leads from Instagram shorts. how I create shorts on
YouTube that are AI generated and get tons of views. right let's have a look. for example, if
we go on to my shorts recently here, you can see all the shorts were posted, and most of these
are generated. check this one out: 66,000 views on this AI generated short on YouTube. so you
know, the more people you reach, the more people that know about your business, the better you
do, right? how can you reach more people? you can use systems like this to basically automate
content creation. so that's all inside the AI Profit Boarding. link in the comments description.
how to do ARSEO with notebook LM, which is a super powerful and free tool you can use. you can
actually combine it with Gemini now as well.
I'll show you what I mean in a second. and if you love notebook you're going love this video,
I think. so what you see here is this a traffic chart of juliangolder.com, and you can see with
AISEO, we're like, we're just getting awesome results. we've taken this website from literally
zero clicks per day to getting thousands of clicks with AISEO, as you can see. and you can see
the traffic chart is just popping off right now. so it's growing up really nicely. we generate
traffic to this website, and obviously, this funnels traffic to our agency, as you can see.
so we're posting blogs on the blog over here all the time, and these pages actually rank in
traffic and do well. all right, so if you want to steal the processes work for me personally,
then you can get this today. all right, so if you never checked out notebook LM, this is what
it looks like. it's a free tool within limits, and on notebooklm.google, you can get access
to it. and then you can go inside here and get all these featured notebooks. now you can do
the basics, right? so for example, let's say I wanted to create a new notebook and then generate
some SEO content for that, right? let me show you how that works. we're going to go to YouTube here.
I'm going to pull in some sources that I can create content around. so for example, let's say
I want to create a blog about, I don't know, genspark right? so I'm going to take the transcript.
we'll plug that into notebooklm in fact, you know what?
I'll just copy the video, and then we can load the video. and from here, we have to load in
our sources. so I'm going to click on YouTube up here. all right? and then what I'm also going
to do is I'm going to add a new source, right? to add sources, we're going to plug in website.
I'm just going to plug in my website URL, and basically, this will custom train the notebook
on genspark and the new update, which we're going to create content around. and then also my
website, which is where I want to funnel traffic to, right? and so it's concentrating on YSL
and also the latest update that I want to create content around for SEO. so from here, what
we can do is we can then take this notebook and create, for example, a video of you that we
actually rank directly on YouTube, right? so if we type in that, like so, it will start to generate
that. now why is that what it's important? because you can actually get a lot of traffic directly
from YouTube itself, right? so for example, if we type in like notebook SEO, you can see that
I'm ranking directly on YouTube for that particular keyword. all right, that's great. and so
you can create videos from notebook LM, and then you could actually upload those to YouTube
directly and rank them on YouTube. now the other cool thing about this is if we go on to Google,
we can see that we also rank number one for that keyword several times, right? so for notebook
LM SEO, right? and so the video that you create from notebook LM can actually rank directly
on YouTube and also directly on Google, right? nice that's pretty cool. all right, now if we
go on to perplexy this should also rank inside AI search engines as well. all right, so if we
type in notebook LM SEO over here and we'll search on perplexy and it's being super buggy, but
we'll see what it does in a sec. maybe it's broken. if not, we'll go to chat your team generally,
and you can see that actually uses sources from YouTube to generate the outputs inside, right?
so for example, it's actually used, for example, my video here as a source inside perplexy and
so when. you're generating these videos or when you're creating content on YouTube around that
particular topic, you rank in inside YouTube, on Google, and directly inside search engines
as well, right? as a source, pretty insane. and so one video can rank multiple times. how to
generate the video? you can just generate a video overview inside notebook LM, or you could
use some of the AI efforts to teach inside the AI proctor boardroom as well. now what you can
also do is you could go inside here and you could take a prompt. this is one of my favorite
prompts from the AI proctor boardroom and you can take this prompt like that. we can type in
the topic we want to rank for. so example: genspark AI update. we'll take that, and it's actually
going to analyze the sources from here and then generate a blog post based on that particular
topic. all right, so we've custom trained our sources. now we need to create a blog post. how
do we create the blog post? we can use a prompt like this. it's inside the AI proctor boardroom
if you want to steal it. and then you can see this generate a whole blog for that particular
topic. all right? and so then inside notebook you can generate the topic itself, plus you can
generate the video, right? so a blog and a video that's going to rank directly on google and
AI search engines like publicity as you can see right here. now here's another example what
you can do. so you can actually load the notebook. it's a nice little hack just came out this
week, right? so we can take that notebook that's custom trained on the sources we want to create
content around. we can plug that in, and then what we can actually do here that's really interesting
is we can rank custom tools that we build on an exact match domain on google for that particular
keyword. let me show you what i mean. so if we go into ahs and let's say you want to rank directly
on google for a keyword, let's say for example, enterprise seoi calculator. you get 600 searches
per month, so that's 6,000 searches per year if you write for it. that would be great, right?
now you can actually see a website that i've custom built with AI ranking number one for that
particular keyword, right? and it funnels traffic to book in an SEO strategy session with my
agency. so we can use this as a way to generate more leads, and all we have to do is create
a simple tool on an exact match domain. for example, like if the keyword is enterprise seoi
calculator, then we just create a website called enterprise seoi calculator. and then from there,
we can start working our magic, right? and so how would we do this with notebook let we can
take in the notebook that we've just generated, so notebook and then we can go to tools canvas
right? and we can say, okay create a custom sass tool about the new genspark ai update plus
have a cta on page to funnel traffic to the ai profit boardroom which is here via this link."
all right? so create a custom sass tool, the update, plus have a cta on the page to funnel traffic
to there, right? and then from here, what we're also going to say optimize the landing page
content plus headlines, etc., to get the keyword genspark ai update, right? and so just to recap
here, we can create a custom sass tool that ranks number one for our exact match domain. so
if our keyword is this, we would create an exact match domain for that, right? and then we can
rank it on google funnel traffic to our website, and all we need to do is create one single
page that can rank, right? how do we do that? we can load in the notebook plus generate a tool
on canvas so we're going to click enter like so, and that will start generating the tool inside
canvas based on the notebook that we've got over here. and we're good to go on this. standby
loading says, good morning! i have a question. when i have a lot of information, but i want
to separate a part of them for a video, how does it work?" my result? yeah all right. so if
you want to generate a video inside notebook alemba you want to separate the information. what
you can do is inside notebook alemba here, with the sources loaded and your notebook custom
trained, you can go to video overview. but you're going to click on edit here, and then you
can actually change the design visual style. if you're from germany so for example, standby
loading, i know you're from germany so we can go to germany and create the content in german
i believe. oh yeah, deutsch so you can use deutsch i guess, right? and then from here, we'll
switch back to english but we can choose our custom design like this. we can choose between
whether it's a brief video or an explainer. i would recommend going with the explainer. and
then here, you tell it what to focus on, right? so if you have individual pieces of information
that you want to generate, like standby loading does, you just put it inside the custom instructions,
and you tell it exactly what to focus on. and that's how it works, right? super easy and simple.
so then inside of canvas we now have the tool, as you can see. we can share that. but the main
thing is here, you want to get the code, save it as a file offline, and then upload it to netlify
so you can host it, right? that's what i did for the page that you can see here. we actually
coded this with bolt but using this node new notebook lm framework, you can use notebook lm
instead to generate the outputs. so it's simple, super simple and easy. and then you can see
the here we can test it out. we can create a report, etc. you see how it's got a cta to join
the air profit boardroom at the top. click on that, it goes straight to our landing page. boom
shaka laka, my friends! and then it's got cta at the bottom as well, as you can see. so anyone
who lands on this page is interested about ai what would be the natural next step? join our
automation community where they can learn new workflows and implement this stuff inside their
business. and so it links naturally together, and it funnels traffic from that keyword to this
that much domain and from the exact match domain to our funnels where we generate clients and
customers. and that's what... all right, pk says, good morning! a bit different question. what's
your ai tool stack that you recommend called code max cursor and gemini there are so many changes,
that's hard to determine what's best." all right, so if you go to the ai profit board all right,
once you're in the start here section. so in the start here section, here, if you want to know
what tools i use, i actually have an updated tools list here. i'm not going to share it because
if someone's watching this video, that changes, and we update it as we go along. but if you
want to know what tools i personally use so you don't feel overwhelmed, get it inside the air
profit boarding start here post. right what you want to see is that when new updates come out,
i review them. so i spend about 80 hours a week testing, and my team spends about eight hours
a week testing. we condense all those hours of testing into a five-minute update where you can
quickly learn what to focus on here. so for example, like july you can see back in july we broke
down, okay here are the new updates. here's why i've created this. here's my top three most
useful this week. here's some decent stuff, and here's the stuff to completely ignore." right
and so we. break down the most important updates, and then we keep you updated like that. and
that's the best way to stay up to date because you can get the latest tools that i'm using,
my tool stack, and that's updated week to week, day to day. and then also, you get the weekly
updates, which you can feel down to here and just learn what's worth your time and what to skip.
that's some of the best stuff. flatland says, great content! using ai i've created a lot of
real professional stuff. kayak website, awesome for you! good to see you!" and yeah, that's
basically how you can use this stuff, right? so if we go back to notebook i was stuffing great,
like reports. this another cool thing as well. you can actually create infographic and images
can rank really well for particular keywords, right? so if i type in notebook glen asio yes,
we'll rank in on the first page of google for that particular keyword. all right? and also,
my website is ranking first page as well. so this is interesting too, right? this is really
interesting. all right, so we're basically dominating the first page of google because we're
creating videos about that topic, like i showed you how to do with notebook we're creating blog
posts about the topic, like i've shown you to do with notebook right we're actually creating
school posts that rank on the first page as well, which is pretty cool. so it generates traffic
to my community. we also create unique posts and create them and post them on linkedin and then
share that information too. all right? and you can see, for example, if you have a look at this
page, i see how many how much traffic you got. yes you got 128 views, which is not bad. oh there
we go! 741 article views, pretty insane, right? so we get a lot of people looking at that content,
and then you can see how easy it is to rank. like another video ranking down there as well.
all right? so you can rank multiple times on the first page google for the keyword that you're
targeting using these methods that i'm showing you today. covered a lot. all right? and then
also, you can create these exact match domains that rank for the tools as well. so that's basically
my master class on how to use notebook for aico if you want to get a free seo strategy session,
you can get that Julian Goldie com book. it in. we can run for a custom aico strategy for your
business. if you want to order seo online, you can get it from the backlink portal that's available
at juliangoldie.com. link in the comments description as well if you want to get access to that.
and you can basically go on here, go to the portal, order whichever package you want, and then
from here, sign up and order online. if you don't want to wait around for a call, most people
don't want to jump on a sales call. so you know, if you don't want to jump on a sales call,
you just want to order seo online, you can do that right here, as you can see. and then finally
if you don't want seo but you do want to learn about automation, you can join the aiprofitable
link in the comments description. google just dropped something crazy with notebook, lm, ultra,
this. thing can now handle 600 sources in one notebook. you get watermark-free slide decks and
way more power. if you use ai for research or content, this changes everything. let me show
you what just happened. all right, so notebook lm just got a massive upgrade. and i'm talking
game-changing stuff here. google put notebook lm inside their ai ultra plan. that's their top-tier
subscription. and when i saw what they added, i had to make this video because if you're doing
research, making content, or building presentations, this update is wild. let me break down
what just happened. and stick around because i'll show you exactly how to use this stuff. so
first, notebook lm is google's ai research tool. you upload sources like pdfs articles, videos,
whatever. then it makes summaries, slide decks, infographics, even audio and video overviews.
it's basically an ai research assistant that does all the heavy lifting for you. now here's
what changed. google just rolled notebook lm into their ai ultra subscription. this is huge.
you now get access to gemini's most powerful models inside notebook lm we're talking the absolute
best ai google has. faster processing, smarter outputs, deeper reasoning on everything you feed
it. but the model upgrade is just the start. let's talk about limits. before ultra the free
version gave you 50 sources per notebook. the pro version gave you 300. ultra you get 600 sources
per notebook. think about that for a second. you can dump entire research libraries into one
notebook. hundreds of pdfs dozens of every article you've ever saved, all in one place, all
processed by ai this matters because most people hit the source limit fast. you're researching
a topic, you add 20 articles, then 30 more, then some pdfs boom you're maxed out. with 600 sources,
that problem is gone. you can build massive knowledge bases that actually work. and it's not
just sources. ultra massively increases your usage limits across audio overviews, way more video
overviews, way more deep research sessions, way more slide deck and infographic generation,
way more. google didn't give exact numbers, but they said the increases are huge. we're talking
professional-level capacity here. now let's talk outputs. this is where it gets really good.
ultra removes watermarks from your slide decks and infographics. that means when you generate
a presentation, it's clean. no google branding, no watermarks, just professional-ready materials
you can use in meetings, pitches, client presentations, whatever. you look like you spent hours
making it when it took you five minutes. and here's something else. ultra brought back the long
option for slide decks. before you could only make short summary decks. now you can generate
full, detailed presentations. we're talking comprehensive decks with tons of slides, perfect
for lectures, workshops, deep dives, anything where you need real substance. now i want to talk
about something. if you're serious about using tools like notebook lm ultra to scale your business,
save time, and automate your workflows, you need to check out my ai profit boardroom this. is
where i show you how to use ai tools like notebook lm and dozens of others to actually grow
your business and get more customers. we cover automation strategies, ai workflows, and real
tactics that save you hundreds of hours. it's the best place to learn how to turn these tools
into actual business results. link is the description. back to it. so who is this for? ultra
is built for power users, researchers who need to process tons of information, content creators
making videos and courses, business analysts building reports, students handling heavy coursework,
anyone who uses notebook lm seriously and hits those limits. if you're casual, the free or pro
versions are fine. but if you're doing real work, ultra is the move. say you're a student writing
a thesis. you've got 100 sources to review: books, journals, articles, interviews. you dump
them all into ultra then you ask notebook lm to summarize each source, pull out key quotes,
find connections between sources, generate an audio overview you can listen to while driving,
then create an infographic showing how all the ideas connect. all of that happens automatically.
you just saved yourself weeks of work. all right, so how do you get ultra you need to subscribe
to google's ai ultra plan. this is their premium tier. it includes ultra access for notebook
lm plus their other ai tools. you can't just buy notebook lm ultra by itself. it's part of the
whole package. google is bundling everything together. smart move on their part. now let me
give you some pro tips for using ultra first maximize your sources. don't just add a few articles.
go deep. add everything relevant. the more sources you add, the better notebook lm understands
your topic. it can make connections across sources, pull insights from multiple places, give
you way outputs. second customize your video and audio overviews. you can give notebook lm specific
prompts. tell it what angle to focus on, what tone to use, what points to emphasize. don't just
hit generate and hope for the best. guide it. you'll get way better results. third use long
slide decks for anything serious: client pitches, lectures, training materials, workshops. the
long format gives you real depth. you're not stuck with surface-level summaries. you get comprehensive
presentations that actually deliver value. fourth experiment with deep research. this feature
lets notebook lm dive into specific questions. it pulls from all your sources, synthesizes information,
gives you detailed answers with citations. it's like having a research assistant that actually
knows your material. fifth combined features. don't just use one thing. generate a slide deck,
then make a video overview explaining the deck. then create an infographic summarizing the key
points. then use deep research to answer questions people might have. stack these features together
and you've got a complete content system. here's the thing. notebook lm ultra isn't just a note-taking
tool anymore. it's a full research and content engine. you can feed it massive amounts of information,
then turn that information into every format you need: presentations, videos, audio, infographics,
reports. all professional quality, all fast, all automated. and because you're using gemini's
best models, the quality is top tier. the summaries are accurate, the presentations make sense,
the overviews sound natural. it's not just spitting out generic ai slop. it's actually processing
your specific sources and creating useful outputs. now i know some people are thinking, is this
worth paying for? here's my take. if you're doing serious research or content work, yes. the
time you save pays for itself immediately. think about how long it takes to read 100 sources,
pull out key points, create a presentation, write a script, make an infographic. you're looking
at days or weeks of work. ultra does it in minutes. the roi is obvious. but if you're just taking
notes or doing light research, maybe not. the free version or pro might be enough. ultra is
for people who need scale, who hit limits, who are building real projects with ai one more thing.
ultra gives you priority access to new features. when google releases something new for notebook
lm ultra users get it first. that's huge. if you want to stay ahead, you're not waiting months
for features to roll out. you get them. so bottom line. notebook lm ultra is a massive upgrade:
600 sources, better models, higher limits, professional outputs, watermark removal, long slide
decks. this turns notebook lm from a nice tool into a serious productivity weapon. if you're
doing research, creating content, or building presentations, this is worth checking out. now
i want to talk about something important. if you're serious about using tools like notebook
lm ultra to scale your business, save time, and automate your you need to check out my ai profit
boardroom this. is where i show you how to use ai tools like notebook lm and dozens of others
to actually grow your business and get more customers. we cover automation strategies, ai workflows,
and real tactics that save you hundreds of hours. it's the best place to learn how to turn these
tools into actual business results. link is in the description. and if you want the full process,
sops and hundred plus ai use cases like this one, join the ai success lab links. in the comments
and description. you'll get all the video notes from there, plus access to our community of
38,000 members who are crashing it with ai it's completely free, and you'll learn how to use
tools like notebook lm along with everything else in ai right now, notebook lm went from cute
note-taking app to absolute monster. they twinix the customization limit, and it's completely
free. i'm about to show you how to turn your boring documents into genius-level ai assistants.
this is wild. all right, so december 4th, 2025, google quietly released an update that's going
to change everything. notebook lm just expanded their chat customization from 500 characters
to 10,000 characters. and i know what you're thinking: who cares about character limits, right?
wrong this is massive because now you can turn notebook lm into basically any expert you want:
product managers, teachers, scientists, seo specialists, whatever. you and it grounds every
response in your document. so no hallucinations, no made-up facts, just pure accurate insights
from your own sources. let me show you why this is absolutely insane. before this update, you
had 500 characters to describe what you wanted. that's like two sentences. you couldn't build
detailed personas. you couldn't set specific formats. you couldn't create real expert-level
assistants. now 10 000 characters, that's enough to build incredibly detailed instructions with
specific tone of voice, exact output formats, constraints, and rules. everything you need to
make ai actually useful. and here's the best part: it's completely free. no credit card, no
subscription. just go to notebooklm.google.com, and you're ready. now let me show you three
examples that google shared when they announced this update. and i'm going to demo these live
so you can see exactly how powerful this is. first example is a ruthless product manager. this
persona gives you decision memos. it looks at your documents and tells you what's actually going
on with user evidence, feasibility checks, blind spots you missed, and contradictions in your
data. it's like having a senior pm review everything you upload. second example is a middle
school teacher. this one breaks down complex topics into kid-friendly explanations. it gives
you analogies, vocabulary lists, and true or false quizzes. perfect for educators or anyone
learning new subjects. third example is a scientific researcher. this persona analyzes papers
with academic rigor, giving you key findings, methodological strengths and weaknesses, and contradictions
with proper citations. it's phd level analysis without the phd now i'm going to show you these
in action. but first, let me tell you how to access this. go to notebooklm.google.com and upload
your documents: pdfs text files, whatever you have. then click the gear icon in the chat, and
you'll see a custom prompt field. that's where the magic happens. that field now supports 10,000
characters instead of 500, and that's where you paste these detailed persona prompts. all right,
let me show you demo number one: the product manager persona. before i show you these demos,
let me tell you about something that will take your ai skills to the next level. it's called
ai profit boardroom and if. you're watching this video because you want to save time and work
smarter with ai tools like notebook lm you need to check this out. artificial intelligence profit
boardroom. teaches you how to automate your business processes using the latest ai tools. we're
talking about saving hours every single day, streamlining your workflows, and getting more done
with less effort. and the best part? you learn from real examples and practical strategies that
actually work. no theory, no fluff, just actionable steps you can implement immediately. if
you want to master tools like notebook lm and dozens of other ai platforms that can transform
how you work, click the link in the description. ai profit boardroom is waiting for you. now
back to these insane demos. okay product manager persona. i uploaded a sample roadmap document,
just a basic product features list. now i'm pasting the exact prompt that google shared. it
tells the ai to act as a ruthless product manager where every response must be a decision memo
with user evidence bullets, feasibility checks, blind spots, and contradictions in a very specific
format. now i'm asking it to review the q3 features, and watch what happens. boom it gives me
a full decision memo. the user evidence section shows which features customers actually ask
for. feasibility checks highlight which ones are realistic versus pipe dreams. the blind spots
section points out what we're missing, and contradictions it found two features that directly
conflict with each other. this is insane. i just uploaded a document and got instant expert-level
analysis. no back and forth, no vague responses, just actionable insights. and this works because
the ai is grounded actual document. it's not making stuff up. it's analyzing what i gave it.
okay demo 2: the middle school teacher persona. i grabbed a science textbook section about photosynthesis.
it's way too complex for most kids. i pasted the teacher prompt, which tells the ai to simplify
everything, give analogies, create vocabulary lists, and add quizzes. i ask it to explain photosynthesis,
and look at this output. first a tldr summary that's super simple: just plants make food using
sunlight. then an analogy where photosynthesis is like a factory kitchen. the leaves of the
kitchen, sunlight is the electricity, water and carbon dioxide are the ingredients, and glucose
is the meal they cook. brilliant then a vocabulary list with chlorophyll, glucose, and stomata,
each term explained in simple language. and at the end, a true or false quiz asking if plants
need sunlight to make food. this is perfect for educators or anyone trying to learn. it breaks
everything down, makes it digestible, and adds interactive elements, all from one prompt. now
demo 3: the scientific researcher persona. i uploaded two biology research papers with dense
academic stuff, methodology sections, and statistical analysis, the works. i pasted the researcher
prompt, which demands formal academic analysis with key findings, with bold headers, strengths
and weaknesses, and contradictions with citations. i ask about the methodology, and watch this.
it gives me a structured breakdown with a bold section for key findings that lists the main
methodological approaches from both papers. then a bold section for methodological strengths
that points out robust sample sizes, proper control groups, and valid statistical tests. then
a bold section for weaknesses that highlights potential confounding variables and limited generalizability.
then the best part: a bold section for contradictions. it compares both papers and shows where
they disagree with exact citations. paper one claims x paper two claims y and these contradict
on this specific point. this is phd level analysis, and i got it in 30 seconds. now here's what
makes this update so powerful. you can adapt these prompts for anything. marketing create an
seo auditor persona that reviews your content, finds keyword gaps, and suggests improvements.
legal make a contract analyze a persona that highlights risky clauses and suggests revisions.
finance build a budget analyst persona that spots overspending and recommends cuts. the possibilities
are endless. and because you're uploading your own documents, the ai stays accurate. it can't
hallucinate facts. it can't make up data. everything comes from your sources. let me show you
this table that breaks down the three sample personas. product manager is best for ruthless
insights and needs about 800 characters minimum to define the structure. middle school teacher
is perfect for kid-friendly explanations. with around 700 characters, plus quiz rules. scientific
researcher is ideal for objective analysis, with about 900 characters for proper formality.
all of these fit comfortably in the new 10,000 character limit. so you can go way more detailed
if you want. now let me give you some real-world use cases. if you're a content creator, build
a video script reviewer where you upload your outlines and ask the ai to critique structure,
pacing, and hooks. if you're a student, create an exam prep tutor where you upload your textbooks
and get custom quizzes and study guides. if you're a business professional, make a contradiction
finder where you upload reports from different departments and let the ai spot inconsistencies.
this tool pairs with gemini 3; that's google's latest ai model. so you're getting cutting-edge
performance for free. now here's a pro tip: don't use vague queries. the more specific your
question, the better the response. instead of asking, to tell me about this document," ask,
what are the three main contradictions in the methodology section?" for specifics and get better
outputs. another tip is to copy and paste the exact prompts google shared. i'll link them in
the description. start with those, test them, see how they work, then adapt them for your needs.
change the tone, adjust the format, add your own constraints, and make it yours. and here's
the biggest mistake people make: they forget to upload sources first. notebook lm needs documents
to ground its responses. if you just chat without sources, you're wasting the main feature.
always upload first, then customize your persona, then start asking questions. that's the workflow.
now let's talk about why this matters. most ai tools are generic. chat gpt gives you generic
responses. claude gives you generic responses. they try to be everything to everyone. notebook
lm is different. it's an ai that becomes exactly what you need based on your documents, based
on your instructions, based on your goals. it's personalized ai without the personalization
tax. and with this 10,000 character limit, you can get incredibly specific. the old limit let
you say, act like a teacher." the new limit lets you say, act like a middle school science teacher
who uses pop culture references, breaks concepts into three-step processes, and ends every explanation
with a quiz question that reinforces the core concept." see the difference? the old version
was a suggestion. the new version is a complete persona with style, with structure, with rules.
that's what 10,000 characters unlocks: real customization, real expertise, real value. and again,
this is free. google isn't charging for this; they're just giving it away. google says, here
take it. no credit card required." that's insane. now here's what you need to do right now:
go to notebooklm.google.com and create an account. if you don't have one, upload a document
you work with regularly. could be a report, a research paper, a client brief, whatever. and
then go to the chat settings, click the gear icon, find the custom prompt field, and paste one
of those sample prompts i showed you: product manager, teacher, researcher. pick one, test it,
and ask a question about your doc. see what happens. you're going to be blown away because you're
going to get expert-level insights from a free tool in about two minutes. and once you see how
it works, start customizing. build your personas. create an seo expert, a legal advisor, a data
analyst, whatever you need. the 10 000 character limit gives you room to be creative, to be
specific, to build something actually useful. this isn't hype. this is a legitimate game changer,
especially for people who work with lots of documents: researchers, students, business professionals,
content creators, anyone who needs to extract insights from text. notebook lm just became your
secret weapon. and with this update, it went from good to incredible. all right, before you
go, one more thing about AI profit boardroom. if watching this demo got you excited about what's
possible with AI tools, you need to join because notebook lm is just one tool. there are dozens
of other AI platforms that can completely transform how you AI profit boardroom shows you how
to automate repetitive tasks, streamline your workflows, and get more done in less time or using
free or affordable AI tools just like this one. no complicated tech jargon, no overwhelming
theory, just practical step-by-step strategies you can use today. if you're serious about working
smarter with AI, click the link in the description and check out AI profit boardroom. you won't
regret it. what if i told you that you could turn a 50-page report into a video, a slide deck,
an infographic, and a full research paper in under 10 minutes? no design skills needed, no hours
in powerpoint just click a button and it's done. today i'm showing you how notebook lm just
became the most powerful content creation tool for seo and it's going to change everything.
this is brand new. this is huge. and if you're still making content the old way, you're already
behind. so notebook lm dropped four massive updates, and i'm not talking about small tweaks.
i'm talking about features that turn this simple note-taking app into a full content studio.
we're talking slide decks, infographics, deep research that searches hundreds of websites for
you, and custom video styles that make your content look professional without touching a single
design tool. let me break down what's actually happening here. notebook lm used to be just an
AI assistant that helped you summarize documents. you'd upload a pdf and it would give you notes.
that was it. but now, now it's completely different. you can upload your sources: pdfs google
docs spreadsheets, even images of handwritten notes. and notebook lm builds an entire knowledge
base from all of it. then here's where it gets crazy. from that same knowledge base, you can
generate slides for a presentation, an infographic for social media, a video for youtube and
a full research report with citations, all from the same sources you upload. your content, click
slide deck, and boom! you get a full presentation ready to go. no manual work, no designing
each slide, no copying and pasting bullet points. it's done. and the best part? the slides stick
to your original content. they don't make stuff up. they don't hallucinate. they pull straight
from your sources. so if you're doing client presentations, or webinars, or teaching a class,
you just saved hours of work. the second update is infographics. these are visual summaries
of complex information. you can choose if you want it vertical for instagram horizontal for
a blog post, or square for linkedin you can control the colors, the layout, the number of key
points, all through prompts. you just type what you want, and notebook lm creates it. this takes
what used to be hours in canva or photoshop and turns it into seconds. you're going from research
to design to share in literally minutes. now here's where it gets really interesting. the third
update is deep research. this is wild. you give notebook lm a topic, it goes out and browses
hundreds of websites. it compiles everything, it synthesizes the information, and it gives you
back a structured report with citations, all automatically. and remember, you can also upload
google sheets word docs, images, whatever you have. so you're building this massive knowledge
base, and notebook lm is doing all the heavy lifting for seo research. game changer for school
projects, unbeatable for content planning. this is what you've been waiting for. and one more
thing: if you're creating all this content with notebook lm but nobody is finding it online,
you've got a traffic problem. that's where seo comes in. if you want more leads, more traffic,
and more sales, my team can help you rank higher on google check the link in the comments and
description to order ai seo online and let us handle your backlinks while you focus on growing
your business. so back to it. the fourth update is custom video overview styles. notebook lm
already had video overviews. those are like narrated slide shows made from your content. but
now, you can type in custom style prompts. you want a modern tech vibe? type it. you want minimal
black and white slides? type it. you want upbeat and professional for a global audience? type
it. you're not stuck with generic videos anymore. you control the mood, the design, the entire
look. and that means your content can actually match your brand instead of looking like everyone
else's. let me show you how this all works together with a real example. let's say you want
to create content about learning guitar in 30 days. this is perfect for seo because thousands
of people search for this every single month. here's exactly what you do. step one is deep.
you open notebook lm you start a deep research session. here's the exact prompt you type: research
everything about how complete beginners can learn guitar in 30 days. include best practice methods,
daily practice routines, common mistakes beginners make, easiest songs to start with, what type
of guitar to buy, how to hold the guitar properly, finger exercises, chord progressions, online
resources and apps, success stories from people who learned quickly. gather information from
a guitar teacher blogs, music education sites, youtube tutorials, and beginner guitar forums."
notebook lm goes out and finds hundreds of sources. it reads everything: guitar teacher websites,
reddit threads, youtube descriptions, music blogs. it organizes all of it. it builds you a complete
research report with citations. now you've got this massive knowledge base about learning guitar
sitting in your notebook. step two: you click slide deck. here's what you type: create presenter
slides showing the complete 30-day guitar learning roadmap for absolute beginners. day 1 through
10 cover basic chords and finger positioning. day 11 through 20 cover switching between chords
and rhythm. day 21 through 30 cover playing simple songs. include visual diagrams for finger
placement. add practice time for each day. use motivating language, brand colors, black and
orange. include speaker notes with teaching tips. target audience is adults who think they're
too old to learn guitar." boom you've got a professional slide deck ready for a webinar, or
a youtube video, or a client presentation. you didn't design anything; it's done. step three:
you click infographic. here's what you type: create a infographic format showing the five most
important tips for learning guitar fast. tip one is practice 15 minutes daily beats one hour
weekly. tip two is start with four basic chords. tip three is use a metronome from day one.
tip four is record yourself to track progress. tip five is learn songs you actually love. use
bold colors, red and black, with guitar icons, minimal clean design. make it shareable for instagram
and pinterest where people search for guitar learning tips." now you've got a shareable visual
for social media. people will save it, share it, and it drives traffic back to your content.
step four: you click video overview. here's what you type: create a video overview titled how
anyone can learn guitar in 30 days even if you think you have no musical talent.' cover the
biggest myths about learning guitar, explain the proven practice method, show the exact daily
routine, include before and after examples. use an encouraging and friendly tone. visual style
should be warm and approachable with clear instructional slides. target audience is beginners
who are intimidated and need confidence that they can actually do this." notebook lm creates
the video slides, narration, everything. and here's the beautiful part: all four of these pieces
of content came from the same research, the same sources, the same knowledge base. so now you've
got a research report, a slide deck for teaching, an infographic for social media, and a video
for youtube all about learning guitar in 30 days, all created in under an hour, all from one
tool. and this same exact process works for any topic: meal prep, sleep optimization, trip planning,
fitness routines, marketing strategies, whatever your niche is. the workflow is the same. you
start with deep research, then you generate your slide deck, then your infographic, then your
video. same sources, multiple formats, maximum reach. and you didn't need design skills. you
didn't need video editing. you just needed notebook lm and good prompts. here's the bottom line:
notebook lm went from being a simple summarization tool to a full content creation studio. slide
decks, infographics, deep research, custom style video overviews, it's all there, and it's changing
how we make content. if you're serious about content creation, if you're serious about research,
if you're serious about building an online presence, you need to try this workflow yourself.
upload a document, let notebook lm build you a slide deck, an infographic, video, all in under
10 minutes, then polish it and publish it. and one more thing: if you're creating all this content
with notebook lm but nobody is finding it online, you've got a traffic problem. that's where
seo comes in. if you want more leads, more traffic, and more sales, my team can help you rank
higher on google check the link in the comments and description to order aico online and let
us handle your backlinks while you focus on growing your business. google just rolled out two
massive features to notebook lm infographics and slide, and they're powered by something called
nano banana pro this. is google's gemini 3 image model built right into notebook lm what does
this mean for you? you can now take any notes, any pdfs any documents you have, and turn them
into professional visual content. we're talking charts, timelines, icons, full presentation
slides, all generated automatically. no design skills needed, no expensive software. just upload
your stuff and let the ai do the work. now before i show you exactly how this works, let me
explain why this is such a big deal. most ai image generators just make random pretty pictures.
they don't understand your content. they don't care about accuracy. but, nano, banana, pro.
is different. it actually reads your sources. it understands your research. it creates visuals
that match your specific content. so if you upload a report about sales data, it makes charts
about sales data. if you upload notes about history, it creates relevant timelines. everything
is based on what you actually uploaded. that's the game changer here. let me walk you through
the infographics feature first. you go to notebook lm you upload your documents, notes, pdfs
whatever you've got. then you click on the new infographics option. the ai reads through everything.
it identifies the key points. it figures out what visuals would work best, and boom! you've
got a professional infographic: charts showing your data, icons representing your concepts,
timelines organizing your information, sleek layouts that actually look good. and here's the
crazy part: you can customize everything. change the colors to match your brand, adjust the
fonts, rearrange the layout, make it exactly what you need. then export it as a pdf or image.
use it in reports, presentations, social media, whatever. the slide deck feature works the same
way. upload your content, click the slide deck option. notebook lm generates an entire presentation
for professional slides, clean design, your content organized perfectly. and just like the infographics,
you can customize everything, then export to google slides or pdf ready to present immediately.
i want to talk about something that's going to help you take this even further. if you want
to learn how to scale your business and save hundreds of hours with ai automation tools like
notebook lm you need to check out my ai profit boardroom. this is where i teach people exactly
how to use tools like this to automate their workflows and get more customers. inside ai profit
boardroom, you'll learn how to turn tools like notebook lm into actual business systems, not
just cool tricks, but real automation that saves you time and makes you more productive. we
cover how to automate content creation, client presentations. research processes everything,
and the best part? you get access to a community of people doing the same thing. so you can
see what's working for them and apply it to your business immediately. if you're serious about
using ai to scale, this is where you want to be. go to school.com slash ai profit lab 7462 slash
about. link is in the description. now back to notebook lm now let me tell you who this is perfect
for. students can turn study notes into visual study guides. educators can create lecture presentations
in minutes instead of hours. content creators can make pitch decks in social media graphics
without hiring designers. business professionals can turn reports into engaging presentations.
anyone who needs to communicate information visually just got a massive upgrade. and remember,
this is all free right now. you don't need notebook lm pro. you don't need to pay anything.
just go to notebook lm google and start using it. let me give you some specific use cases so
you can see how powerful this really is. say you're a student studying for exams. you've got
pages and notes. upload them to notebook lm generate an infographic that summarizes everything
visually. suddenly your study material is way easier to remember because our brains love visual
information. or say you're a teacher preparing a lesson. you've got your lesson plan written
out. upload it to notebook lm generate a slide deck. now you've got a full presentation ready
to go with visuals that help students understand the concepts better. or maybe you're pitching
a client. you've got graphics showing the market opportunity. generate slides for your pitch
deck. now you look incredibly professional, and it took you maybe 20 minutes total. the productivity
boost here is massive. things that used to take hours now take minutes, and the quality is actually
good. this isn't some janky ai output that looks amateur. these are professional grade visuals.
now here's something most people don't realize yet. you can combine this with other notebook
lm features. remember notebook lm already does audio overviews. it can turn your notes into
podcast style summaries. now you can do visual overviews too. so you could take the same source
material and create an audio version for listening, a visual infographic for quick reference,
and a slide deck for presenting. three different formats from one upload. that's insane efficiency,
and it all stays synced because it's from the same sources. let me talk about nano banana pro
for a second. this is what's powering everything behind the scenes. it's google's latest image
generation model, part of the gemini 3 family. and what makes it special is how it handles source
material. most ai image generators work like this: you give them a text prompt, they make an
image based on that prompt, but they don't really understand context. they're just pattern matching.
nano banana pro is different. it actually processes your documents, reads the text, understands
the relationships between ideas, then generates images that accurately represent that information.
so if your document talks about a process with five steps, it creates a visual showing those
five steps in order. if you've got data comparing three different things, it makes a chart comparing
those three things. the accuracy is what sets it apart, and that's why these visuals are actually
useful instead of just decorative. now let me give you some tips for getting the best results.
first organize your sources before uploading. the clearer your input, the better your output.
if you upload a messy pile of random notes, you'll get messy visuals. but if you upload well-organized
information, the ai has clear material to work with. they second use the customization options.
don't just accept the first version the ai generates. adjust colors to match your brand. rearrange
elements to emphasize what matters most. the ai gives you a great starting point, but you can
make it perfect. third export in the right format for your use case. need to edit more later?
export to google slides need a final version? to export to pdf need. something for social media?
export as an image. pick the format that makes sense for what you're doing. fourth don't overthink
it. just start creating. upload something and see what happens. the interface is super simple.
you'll figure it out in five minutes, and because it's free, there's zero risk to experimenting.
right let me talk about some advanced strategies. one thing you can do is create a content library.
every time you research a topic, upload it. to now you've got a visual content library you can
pull from anytime. need a quick social post? grab an infographic. need slides for a meeting?
you've already got them ready. this is especially powerful if you work in a specific niche.
build up your library over time, and you'll always have relevant visuals ready to go. another
strategy is batch creation. set aside one hour per week. upload everything you've worked on
that week. generate all your visuals at once. way more efficient than doing it one at a time
as you need it. you can also use this for client work. if you're an agency or freelancer, this
is a goldmine. clients love visual deliverables. use notebook lm to create professional looking
reports and presentations. your clients think you spent hours on design work. reality is, you
spent 10 minutes uploading their data and letting ai do the heavy lifting. that's how you scale
without hiring a design team. one more thing about the integration with google's ecosystem.
since this exports to google slides it plays nice with everything else you're probably already
using. easy to collaborate with team members. easy to present in meetings. easy to share with
clients. everything just works together. no weird file format issues. no compatibility problems.
just smooth integration. now i know some of you are thinking, what's the catch? there's got
to be limitations, right? honestly not many. the main thing is you need good source material.
garbage in, garbage out. if you upload poorly written notes, the ai can't magically fix that.
but if you give it decent content to work with, the results are excellent. the other thing is
this is still new. google just rolled this out, so there might be some bugs or quirks as they
work through things. but from what i've tested so far, it's pretty solid. way better than i
expected for a free tool. here's what i think is coming next. right now, you can do infographics
and slides. i bet google adds more formats soon. maybe social media graphics optimized for different
platforms. maybe video thumbnails. maybe even short form video content. they're clearly investing
heavily in making notebook lm a complete visual content creation tool, not just a note-taking
app anymore. and with nano banana pro behind it, they've got the technology to do pretty much
anything visual. so expect more features rolling out over the next few months. now before i
wrap up, i want to hit one more time on why this. we're living in a world where visual content
is everything. social media, presentations, reports, education, marketing, everything needs
visuals. but creating good visuals used to require design skills or hiring designers. that barrier
just disappeared. anyone can now create professional visual content. students competing with
other students. creators competing with other creators. businesses competing with other businesses.
if you're not using tools like this, you're falling behind because your is using them, and they're
creating better content faster than you. that's just reality. so the question isn't whether
to use these tools. the question is how fast can you learn them and implement them? and with
notebook lm being this easy and this free, there's no excuse not to start today. all right,
last thing before i go. if you're serious about staying ahead with ai tools and want to learn
how to build real automation systems that scale your business with tools like notebook lm you
absolutely need to join ai profit boardroom. this is where we break down exactly how to implement
these tools in ways that actually matter for your business. not just surface level tips, but
deep strategies for automating your workflow, creating better content faster, and ultimately
getting more customers. inside ai profit boardroom, you'll get step-by-step training on using
notebook lm and dozens of other ai tools to transform how you work. you'll see real examples
from people in the community who are saving hundreds of hours and scaling their businesses.
and you'll get direct access to ask questions and get feedback on your specific situation. this
is the best place to learn how to leverage ai automation for real business results. link is
in the description below. trust me, if you're watching this video, you need to be in that community.
notebook lm has just given you the ability to automate slides, infographics, and podcasts from
anything in like under 60 seconds. so i'm gonna show you exactly how this works, how to use
notebook lm and how to create these crazy infographics like you can see right here. plus how
to create these absolutely insane presentations in one single click. you can see here we've
got a full designed presentation step by step, and i literally just automated it before this
live stream in one click. it was ridiculous. now if you've never used this before, i'm going
to talk you through how notebook lm works. so don't worry. just dropped. it's free. it's brand
new. and when i saw what it could do, i pretty much had to go live immediately because if you're
a business owner who creates any kind of content, presentations, guides, trainings, client materials,
this is about to save you hours every single week. and the other thing about this is you don't
need any design skills. you don't need to use canva you don't need any powerpoint you don't
need to hire anyone. you just upload yourself, click a button, and it gives you a finished slide
deck with infographics, charts, and professional designs. or an infographic that explains your
process in one image. or a podcast where two ai hosts can discuss your content like it's a real
radio show. or from your existing documents, sources, youtube videos, whatever you want to plug
in. it's all completely free. now here's why it matters for you specifically. okay if you've
ever felt overwhelmed by all the ai tools out there, if you've tried stuff before and it didn't
work, if you don't have time to learn complicated tech, this is different. it's simple. it works.
i'm going to show you exactly how to use it step by step, so stay until the end because i'm
also going to give you my prompts, my workflows, and some custom automations you can copy inside
the video notes. let's get straight into it. okay so what you can see here, this is notebook
lm you can get free access at notebooklm.google.com. and to make it as simple as possible, all
you do is you go to create a new notebook like you can see right here. and then you can upload
sources. so for example, you can copy and paste tags. you can add a link. you can add a website,
google drive doc. you can have multiple different sources. in fact, you can actually add 300
different sources, which is pretty wild. so what i'm going to show you exactly today is a step-by-step
guide for the process described in this video as psx has requested. all right, so if you want
to get access to this, you can get it at notebook lm and then for example, we can grab a video
from a youtube channel or any source you want to paste in. let's take something brand new, like
for example called opus 4 5 which you know most of the internet doesn't have much information
on yet because it literally just came out 24 hours ago. we can paste in a youtube source like
so, and that's going to load up a new notebook right now. inside that notebook, we are custom
training it on our information and our sources. okay you see that example right here? we've
got the source loaded on the left-hand side. then we have this custom gpt and then if we want,
i mean, it's basically a notebook. and then inside here, we can just click this and this, and
literally in one click, what we are generating is an audio view, a video view, some flash cards,
a quiz, an infographic, and a slide deck all in one single click. all right, and you can automate
all of those literally instantly just by loading in the source and then quickly creating these.
now you might be wondering, okay, what's the quality of these? what do they look like? here's
one i actually created earlier. so if we go back to notebook lm here, we can go over to building
applications with google's new ai stack. you can see i've loaded in some information and sources
about google's ai stack over here. and then if we click on this example, as you can see, what
you can see here is a custom infographic, very detailed. and the difference here, you may not
notice this, but the difference here is that you've never been able to create an infographic
as detailed as this, as well designed as this, with perfect text. look at the icon, for example.
you got smashed up laptop there with the excuse these tools probably don't work well. we've
talked about the old limiting beliefs versus the new limiting beliefs that help you build stuff
and automate stuff with ai right? and so you can see how quick and easy it is now to generate
these custom built infographics as well as video views, podcasts, and everything else. and you
can do this for free. it's absolutely mind-blowing. so if you've never done this before, definitely
check it out. now i'm going to show you some other cool stuff that you can do and also have
a look at the outputs from opus so you can see we've already got a quiz ready, already got the
flashcards ready, and we are just going to have to wait a couple of minutes for the rest of
this to be automated and built. and this is the thing, if you've not realized this already,
right now notebook 11 google's technology in general, i would say it's a total level above everyone
else's because if you were using ai a few years ago, you know that google was way behind everyone
else. whereas now, what they're creating is something that is pretty much changing the internet,
right? and changing the way that we learn, changing the way that we create content is absolutely
mind-blowing. now if you want to know, okay, what are all the new key features? because i know
a lot of you are using notebook lm already. you already understand it. you're already like,
okay, what's actually new in november 2025? so let me talk you through that. these notes are
inside the air profit boardroom. so if you want to go and grab that, you can just go to the
air profit boardroom in the link in the comments description. go to the classroom or just go
to airprofitboarding com and then. from here, what you're going to do is go to sop updates,
as you can see. and then we've got november 2025. this gets updated every day. so you've got
25th there with opus we've got 23, 22, etc. right and if you scroll down, you can see we've
got the key notes and features here. so one of the biggest new updates, and this is due to nano
banana, which is a brand new image update from notebook. and you can see that we can now turn
documents into visual infographics powered by nano banana. what do they look like? they look
like this. how do you automate them? you just go up here. so you load in your source inside
notebook lm and then you are going to click infographic over here, and this generates an infographic
for you. all right, now if you want to see what the infographic looks like, so i literally just
clicked generate, as you saw a couple of minutes ago. then you can see that right here inside
this section, right? and see for ai showdown, claude opus versus gemini 3 pro, the comparison
based on initial hands-on testing, the powerful record opus and a top competitor. and then you
can see the head-to-head verdict with this infographic. it is mind-blowing. now you can share
that. you can download that. you can go full screen on it, and you can use this on social media,
for example. so for example, we wanted to use this. what we could do is just download that image
over here. then we can go over to whatever social media platform you prefer. so i'm just going
to do this x for example. then we're going to upload the image of the infographic we just created,
and we can say claude opus 4 5. versus versus gemini 3 pro. who wins? here's my take and plus
our success right. and you can see that we can easily create not just the infographic itself
in one click. but we can also generate social media content that we could post on linkedin on
facebook and in any sort of platform where you're trying to reach a lot of people, right? and
if you have questions as we go along, this is live, so feel free to ask, and i will be happy
to help you. all right, so we go back to this infographic as well. you can zoom in, you zoom
out, but you can actually read the text. you can see the text is pretty much perfect, right?
so this is using nano banana pro which is the new update from google and it's integrated inside
notebook lm so all you do is you click a button. boom shakalaka! you've got an infographic ready
to go. i just love the design of this. i love the way it's laid out. i actually think it's better
than most designers. it's better than most infographics i've paper in the past, and you can
just automate it in one click. all right, that's just one single update from notebook lm in
november 2025. let's have a look at the rest of the stuff. all right, so we also got slide deck.
so we can create comprehensive and complete presentations from our sources, customized to our
source in one single click. how do we do that? so if we go back here, we'll go back inside notebook
lm we're gonna x off that and then scroll down, and you can see this is generating the slide
deck. so i'm going to go to a previous one i've generated. it does take a bit longer to create
a slide deck because they have so much detail inside them. and you can see i've generated a
few different ones over here. so each time this generates, this should be unique as well. so
for example, here we've got build your business with google's new ai slide. that's actually
an infographic. we've actually got a presentation over here. i'm going to go full screen on
that. we can actually start and play the slideshow as well. and you can see here that based
on my video that i generated and loaded into notebook lm it's taken the whole transcript and
then created a beautiful presentation about it, right? so you can see here it says, google just
dropped gemini and it's changing everything. here's the google ai building stack: how to build
apps, automate work, and create infinite minutes." and then it's got a quote from the actual
transcript, right? so you can see it's quoted, this is the craziest ai release i've ever seen,"
which is something that she used inside the presentation, right? then we've got the presentation,
as you can see right here. again it's using nana banana and all the custom notes from the transcript.
and we again automated that in one single click. even took some sort of screenshot from the
video and then plugged that in, right? and it's actually got a link as well inside that video,
right? so you can see here it's super detailed. it's even got the office stack from the video
as well, and it's absolutely mind-blowing what this can generate and how quick and easy it is
to generate this stuff. all right, now if you want to do that, all you do is you go back to
notebook lm go to that custom automation that you've plugged in the sources to, and then you're
just going to go over here and you're going to click slide deck, right? you just click side
deck. now you can actually edit the slide deck before you start creating content with it. so
you can see, for example, you can select detailed or you can select to present slides. so this
is clean visual slides. this is something more comprehensive. you can select between short and
default. you can choose your language. you can actually create in multiple languages, as you
can see. and then you can actually describe what you want to include inside the slide deck if
you want to customize it more before you actually publish it. so easy to do this stuff, and
it's never been easier. and this is better than most humans can do, right? and this is the thing
that i'm finding with most of these tools that are coming out now, especially the new releases,
right? so i think the ai has really stepped up over the last couple of weeks. if you look at
the latest releases from google i've got tons of videos and training inside. they are profitable
to run that. but if you look at the latest updates, they are mind-blowing. they're doing things
that are better than humans at this point, right? and it's the same with notebook lm it can
create better presentations. it can create better infographics for most human designers, and
it's absolutely mind-blowing what it can do. now again, that's only two updates that came from
notebook collect so we've got deep research, we've got custom personas, we've got audio overviews,
we've got flashcards, video views, and this is free, right? there are capacity limits in terms
of how many you can create based on the demand, but basically that's what you can do and how
you can use it, right? and again, these presentations are absolutely amazing, right? you can
click on them, you can view them, you can switch around, you can actually download them, play
them, go full screen, etc., right? and you can load that onto whatever platform you want to
use. you can probably adapt it to instagram carousel, whatever you want to use, right? the thing
is, right, i have an seo agency, and this is absolutely mind-blowing with this new technology
that's coming out because i would have done things so different if notebook lm had these features
when i was building my seo business. picture this, right? it's 3am i'm staring at my wall of
research tabs. my eyes hurt, my brain is fried. i need to turn 47 different sub p's and seo
guides into a training for my team. and back in the day, i would have spent like six to eight
hours just reading everything, and then another four hours making notes, and then another three
hours turning those notes into slides, and then another two hours actually making it look good,
right? it's almost 20 hours for one single training. that was the old way. now imagine if you
could dump all 47 guides into one place, aka notebook lm click a button, and get a full slide
deck that looks like a designer just made it, ready to present in minutes. that's basically
what notebook lm has just dropped for free. and here's where it gets wild. okay let's say you're
building content for a client. well you have their brand guidelines that you can plug into notebook
you have their old blog posts, you have their competitive research, you have their keyword data,
and the old way was that you would read everything, you would take notes, you try to remember
what goes where, miss stuff, go back, read again, make a dot, format it, hope it makes sense,
right? the new way with notebook lm is literally all you do is you plug in a source over here,
you get your custom notebook lm over here, and you can actually ask your questions inside here
and create a mind map or whatever. and then you just create your presentation or your infographic,
as you can see, right? how easy is this stuff? it's absolutely mind-blowing how powerful this
is and how easy it is to do. okay and i don't think most people are aware of, especially business
owners, because they're too busy running their business. so again, the new way is that you upload
everything, ask notebook lm to make an infographic or a presentation or a video showing the
content strategy, and it's done. you ask it to make a slide deck for a client meeting, done.
on a podcast-style breakdown where you can listen to this stuff whilst driving or whatever,
it's done, right? and i remember sitting in my home office, frustrated, tired, thinking there
has to be a better way to process all this information. i was building automations, i was building
tools, but the gap between raw research and something i can actually use was still huge. and
today that gap just closed. this week i've uploaded my notes from like 12 different videos about
ai trends. i've uploaded three pdf reports. i've uploaded my own google docs about what i've
learned. and then i've asked notebook lm to make me a slide deck about the top five ai tools
solopreneurs should learn in 2025. and it gives me the slides back: beautiful design, charts
in the graphics, key points pulled from everything i uploaded, and i didn't write a single slide,
right? this is a mind-blowing thing. i didn't design anything. i just uploaded my research,
clicked a button, and now think about what that means for someone starting out or a solopreneur
running a business, right? you don't need designers. you don't need to spend hours formatting.
you don't need to struggle with making your research actually useful. you just need to know
how to ask the right questions and then how to feed it the right sources. and you can see how
easy that is. you know what sources you want to feed it, okay? and that's exactly what i teach
inside the airprof water it's not just like the basic stuff that everybody already knows. these
are the frameworks to think it, the way to combine tools like this into systems that actually
automate and run parts of your business. because here's the truth: this tool is free. anyone
can use it. but most people upload one pdf and give up, okay? and the people who win today are
the ones who understand the bigger picture, right? who know how to stack these tools together,
have a community showing them what's working right now. and that's why today i want to show
you exactly how this works step by step so you can see what's possible when you know how to
use what's already available to you. so we're going to talk about the goldie source to asset
framework, and this is basically my approach to turning messy research into polished business
assets without design skills or spending hours formatting, right? and the framework has five
steps: source, stack, shape, style, and share. so let's talk about source. so for example, what
we can do here is we can start finding relevant sources. so i'm going to go to create a notebook.
again this is available on notebook lm and from here, we can start uploading our sources. at
this point, source means gathering everything related to your topic that you want to create
around, right? pdfs, google, docs, youtube. links, website urls blog posts, even images, whiteboards,
or handwritten notes. notebook can read it. most people upload one or two things and wonder
why the output is weak. the secret is volume and quality. more sources and better sources equals
better output. so let me talk you through exactly how to do this step by step. and tisha says,
can you direct the style of the infographic? let's have a look at that in a second. all right,
so what i'm going to do first is we are going to upload these sources. this is step one of the
five-step framework that i'm teaching today, right? so where do you get the sources from? let's
say for i want to do a new post on the latest ai news. i can grab videos from my youtube channel,
as you can see. so we're going to grab this one, and let's go over to notebook lm and we will
load that in. i'm going to just paste i in. boom there we go. all right, now we're going to
add another source. and the thing here to note is, let's say for example, you wanted to research
the web, right? you can actually just put, okay, ai news november 2025 here, right? like that.
so you could add and research the web here, plug in the fast research, etc. and then that's
pretty simple and easy to do, all right? or you can go to add sources here, paste in some more
text, add some youtube etc., right? so let's say for example, i want to grab more information
about the latest tools this week, right? what i can do is i can open up this one. all right,
so we're going to go to youtube here. we're going to open up this video on copilot ai we'll
go back to notebook lm we're going to add another source right here. all right, there we go.
and then we're going to add another one. so we're going to just keep going and add a bunch of
sources. again the more and the better quality your sources are, the better the outputs from
this particular process. all right, so we're going to take this training. it's a very in-depth
training. it's a one-hour mega course on the new updates from gemini 3, which just came out.
and we're going to go inside here, and we shall add another source, my friend, right? that we're
going to plug in youtube there we go. and it's just loading up these sources. and once it's
done, it's going to have a tick box next to it, right? so it's loaded in three sources that
are custom trained for this particular notebook right here. now we could add many more sources.
i'm on a live stream, so obviously i'm just going to keep it short. but we could add 300 sources
if we wanted to, if we wanted to create like an insane amount of volume of sources. and again,
you could add more if you don't want to load this manually, and you can search across web or
even your content from google drive if you just wanted to automate this, right? super simple
and easy to do. so that is the sourcing step of the five-step framework. and again, we've got
a five-step framework, and it starts with source, and it's going to be stack, shape, style,
and share. all right, so we've covered sources. now let's talk about stack. okay so you want
to organize your sources by project or outcome, and you want to create separate notebooks for
different purposes. so let me show you how that works. so if we go back to the home here inside
notebook lm you can see all of these different notebooks i've created. so for example, claude
opus building applications. with google's new ai stack. my sales recipe uploaded as a source,
and create a custom notebook right here. google antigravity my book, seo link building mastery.
right? you can actually see the dates, and you can organize your sources. you can actually delete
them, or you can edit the title to create a more organized, right? so for example, here we can
say, okay, edit the title, and let's call this the November, AI, news November. 2025. all right,
so we've got a notebook that's organized here based on the latest updates. okay so that is the
stack process. so again, you can create different notebooks for different purposes. so one for
client presentations, one for your own training materials, one for content ideas, and just keep
them separate so that ai stays focused on what matters for your specific goal. and that is stage
number two. okay now stage number three, and i'm blasting through this because i want to make
sure that you get the most value possible in the shortest amount of time here, is shape. so
that is stage number three. this means choosing the right output format for your goal. so notebook
lm now gives you multiple options. so if we go over here, you can see, for example, we can select
between audio overview, video for you, mind map, reports, flashcards, quiz, infographic, slide
deck, right? we can also add notes down here, and we can edit the outputs before we publish
them. in terms of shaping, slide decks will be for presentations, infographics will be for visual
summaries, audio overviews for podcast-style breakdowns, flashcards for learning, and then quizzes
for testing and understanding. each format serves a different purpose, right? so for example,
here we can go into the infographic section, right? and we can select between our different
languages. we could have portrait or square, depending on what orientation we want, or landscape.
we could choose level of detail, so you go with concise, standard, or detailed, right? and then
inside the describe the infographic you want to create, you can talk about what you want to
talk, right? so for example, here we can say, okay, talk about the use cases of chloride opus
4 5. which is the new update that literally just came out 24 hours ago, right? so you can do
with some really cutting-edge stuff because you're loading in your custom sources, and because
you're loading in custom from youtube you can take videos that are brand new with very in-depth
training, right? and let's be honest, you can find almost anything on youtube about the topic
you want to learn, right? so for example, michelle says, it's incredible what notebook lm does,
and i would 100% agree with you, michelle that's a great point, right? we've covered three stages
so far: sourcing, stacking, shaping, right? and this is a custom framework. this is the goldie
source asset framework now. step number four: style means customizing the output to match your
brand and audience. so you can now set like custom personas, or you can tell it exactly how
you want to write and create. so let me show you how that works, right? so for example, let's
say we wanted to create a video over here. we can choose between explainer or brief, right?
so we could go with brief and really just simplify that video overview. we can go with the language
is english we can choose between visual styles, right? so we can select something that's designed
based on the style that we want, right? so let's say for example, i can load in classic up here,
and then we can tell it exactly what we want the ai host to focus on inside the video overview,
and we can shape it exactly how we want it. so let me show you how that works. we can say, okay,
then show the benefits of joining the ai profit boardroom community with an offer stack at the
end, and you could shape it exactly how you want. we or you can say, okay, then give a custom
offer on how you can learn ai automation and save time using the ai profit boardroom community.
okay and you can say, okay then transition naturally and give a custom offer. right we can then
click generate, and we're shaping that video overview exactly how we want it, based on the custom
sources and the guides we're giving, and the custom instructions we're giving to notebook ellen
right and that is stage number four, which is style. okay now once you've done that, then you're
going to come on to the fifth and the final stage, which is sharing. right sharing means actually
using and sharing what you create. so there's no point creating this stuff if you're not going
to use it. right it's all fun in games playing with tools, but if you're a business owner and
you're a solopreneur, and you're trying to grow your business and trying to automate and save
time, then you've actually got to use this stuff. right so for example, like a lot of my videos
are ai avatar videos on youtube and the reason that i do that is because i want to showcase
the power of ai right the same, for example, if we have a look at this page, i actually redesigned
this whole page yesterday, which is a for our seo agency. and actually redesigned this whole
page using cord opus 4 5. yesterday. so my main point here is don't just play with these tools,
actually use them, actually create them. right diamond says i get this question every single
live stream, which is this a real goldie or avatar? this is a real goldie unfortunately we're
not at the point yet where ai avatars could do live streams yet, but i'm sure that's coming
one day, along with zoom calls and sales calls and else. all right, but my main point here is
like this beautiful page was created using claude opus right and how did we do it? we just asked
opus to redesign the page, create html plug it into to go high level if you want more training
on that, join the air profit boardroom basically. that's how it goes. right diamond says legend,
love the content, big fan, appreciate you. thanks so much, diamond that's super kind, appreciate
you. all right, so you can see how this works. and yeah, you can export slide decks as pdf so
you can download the audio over use and embed that into a blog post. you can share the infographics
on social media like i did a minute. all right, so if we go back to x right now, then i'm talking
about using this stuff practically. and for example, we've got the example here, and diamond
has actually replied to this. all right, so you can see here we've taken the infographic from
notebook ln plug that onto x we could use the same on linkedin or whatever platform we want
to create content around and then share that. and that's literally in the space of what, 20
minutes? that's got 147 views. all right, we've reached 147 new people. you know about our stuff,
know about me because i've created that content and automated it with notebook right this stuff
is crazy powerful if you know how to use it. you can reach a lot of people if you know how to
use it, and that's what i'm showing you today in an actual practical way. right you might have
been thinking, and i want to break down, okay, what's stopping you right now? okay so you might
be thinking this sounds too good to be true, but let me address pretty much every doubt you
have about notebook or these ai tools in general. okay so number one, some people want to say
i'm not technical enough for this, but notebook lm is made for people who aren't technical.
you upload files, you click buttons, you get results. right there's no code, there's no complicated
setup. if you can use google drive or if you can click buttons, you can do this. right and if
you can't click buttons, and you can hire a virtual assistant to click buttons for you. michelle
says i joined, looking forward to more. thanks so much, michelle i really appreciate you. thanks
so much for joining the aircraft recording and that is awesome. welcome on board. all right,
so yeah, i can actually see you just joined now. that's awesome, thanks so much. you know, other
people want to say i tried my ai tools before, and they gave me garbage. all right, so if we
have a look at claude opus and the infographic that we just automated whilst i was on the live
stream with you, so i'm not even concentrating fully. i'm just talking to you and guiding you
through the process, and you can see how easy it is to create a beautiful infographic that,
again, we could share. and you can see here, like the text is pretty much perfect, the copyright
is super nice. it looks better than most human designers can make. it looks better than anything
i could create. right we just did it in one click. some people are going to say i tried ai tools
before, and they gave me garbage, but that's because most ai tools pull from the entire internet
and make things up. right whereas notebook lm only uses what you give it. it can't hallucinate
facts because it only knows what's in your sources, and every answer comes with citations you
can check. right so for example, if we go back here, we escape off there, and then we start
typing here, and we say, okay, let's take one of these auto-suggest questions. so it says, how
does claude opus compare functionally and economically to its top competitors like gemini pro
and it'll actually analyze and examine these sources that were plugged in, and then it gives
the sources for each answer. right so you can see it's used the sources that we've given it.
right so the only time this would mess up is if we give it bad sources, which is why we need
to make sure that we load in good sources into this. right michelle says they turned out quite
nice. 100, they're looking really nice. it's looking really good. all right, some people are
going to say i don't have time to learn another tool, but this tool actually saves you time.
the learning curve is maybe 10 minutes, and you've pretty much been through the learning curve
with me today. so you know the time savings hours per week, and you can generate a full presentation
just by clicking a button. you go off, make some coffee, and you come back, and it's ready to
go. also some people say free tools always have a catch, and the thing is with notebook lm or
with gemini with nano banana pro with ai studio etc., the catch is that google wants you in
their ecosystem. that's it. all right, the core features are actually free. i think you get
up to something like 100 notebooks, 50 sources per notebook, three audio overviews per day,
and that's more than enough. most people watching this, i would say for 99, i've never created
more than three audio reviews in one. i've never created more than 50 sources per notebook.
right so this is more than enough for most people. and other people say my business is different,
this won't work for me, but this works for any business that deals with information. coaches
you need to create training materials. consultants who need client presentations. content creatives,
you need to research topics. freelancers you need to organize project notes. if you read or
write anything, this is probably going to help you. okay and so this is what i'm talking about
here. and then if we have a look, we've got the video overview. so i'm actually going to mute
this because i don't think the sound will be that good, but it does come with these examples,
and this is what it's all about. all right, now our legends. hi julian i'm standing at the chow
fryer. my first day in bangkok welcome to bangkok just out of the gym, i'm watching a live stream.
what a great synergy. that's what we're talking about. what sort of a legend goes to the gym
at what, 6:50 a.m., and then comes out and watch a video and learns about ai like you're absolutely
smashing it. that's a great way to start the game. so good for you, man. if you, i would read
out your name, but it says out on the name, but it's good to see here, and welcome to bangkok
good on you for getting yourself out there. michelle says omg i have a creator. i love his trainings.
he gives us transcripts with the replay and a problem all into notebook to keep track and quick
reference. that is what we're talking about. so there's some great ways to use this stuff. right
it's really exciting, and honestly, i think it's never been such a great time to learn, but
also to be running a business. if you're running a business, if you're in a business, what a
time. right like you don't need a team, you don't need a big squad of people to manage. you
just create stuff like this, and you've got a whole marketing team in one click using ai and
you can automate a lot of this as well. other people, when i say i don't have anything to upload,
but i would just start with whatever you have. right so for example, michelle uses the transcripts
from a creator that she really likes. right and that's a perfect way to use it. you could plug
in past client calls, you could plug in your own notes, articles, you say competitive websites,
youtube videos in your niche. you have way more sources than you think. anything you consume,
you can pretty much plug into this. here and story box maker says can we share to folks about
a google account? the link is not totally public in my opinion. as far as i know, i think you
do need to log in with google account. again this is why it's free. right they want more people
inside the ecosystem, and one of the ways to do that is by making sure people log in. by the
way, if anyone's watching this and you want to share this stuff, so you can click on share in
the top right over here, and then you can share your notebook. and then you can actually add
a welcome note here. you can add people's emails, you can choose between full notebook, chat
only, and you can make this restricted or give anyone with link access. and then you just copy
the link, hit save once you make the changes. boom shakalaka, you can share this with the world.
right so it's crazy powerful, super easy to use, doesn't take a long time, and you can see how
this works step by step. right so let's keep going through the official. davey b says hey everyone,
good to see you. so let's have a look at this video that we're going to play back now. so this
is a video. it does come with a narrated voiceover at the top. you can download that as well.
so if we download that, we can download over here, and i'm just going to go full screen with
this. and also we can play the video. let's see what it's like. right now, i have muted the
sound because i don't think it'll sound very good on the replay, but you can see that it's it's
created a quote from the particular transcript, designed the whole presentation, added a narration,
made it downloadable. it's just playing it back automatically. it's clean, it's nicely designed,
and it's created using the directions we gave it. it's even great some nice charts, as you can
see in terms of the test scores. it talks about what makes opus 4 5 so different, and then you've
got the old way and the new way, which is something that i always like to look at. it's okay,
what were people doing previously, and what are they doing now? and it's taking that information
from the transcripts that i plugged in and then started to use that. so you can see how easy
and powerful this is and how quick it is to make it. so as that's playing, let me talk you through
some other stuff. some people want to say the outputs won't be good enough for clients. i would
argue that these outputs are starting points. you can customize everything. you can choose format,
set the tone, add your own polish. this tool does 80% of the work, and then you just add the
20%. how do you do that? you give it the alternative, so you give it the custom instructions.
michelle says this is a great alternative to gamma i would agree with you. and some people say
i can't afford to pay for tools, but this is free for the core features. it's free. there is
a premium pricing that you can sign up to on notebook alembic you can just use the free stuff
and then see what you think. now other people say i'm overwhelmed by all the tools out there.
julian you talk about a new tool every single day, and that's true, to be fair. like we talk
about opus and then copilot and then gemini and then red plate and then genspark and this is
all within the last 24 hours pretty much. right what i would say here is that's exactly why
you need one place that teaches you what actually matters. so for example, inside the air, profit,
board, and. we just cut free the noise. we show you what's working right now. we help you build
systems, not just random tools. some people, some wild people might say what if google shuts
down and then we lose access to this tool? google has been building notebook alembic since 2023.
they just added it to google workspace for businesses. they released mobile apps this year for
notebook alemb they're investing more, not less, and i think this tool is becoming part and
core of how google thinks about ai productivity. and then some people say i'm already doing
okay without ai but okay is the enemy of great. okay your competitors are learning these tools.
the ones who don't use them and learn them will fall behind. the question isn't whether ai will
change how business works, is whether you'll be ahead of that change or just playing catch up.
okay that was the video generated. as you can see, pretty simple and easy to do, and you can
download this stuff. you can customize it. you can create many different notebooks. we've got
the chatbot as well inside here. what's pretty cool about this, this is great for training your
team. so if your team has questions and you're getting a little bit bored of explaining the
same thing over and over again, but at the same time, maybe your sap and your step-by-step instructions
are too long as a playbook. for example, like our sales sap it's 70 pages. if that's the case,
if your playbook is too big, then they can actually just go inside something like this. it's
custom trained on our playbook, as you see on the left, and then they can start typing and asking
questions. that's great because now it saves you time, and you don't have to train people over
and over again, which, as we all know, can be quite monotonous. all right, this stuff is really
simple and easy to use. and again, you might be saying this content, maybe it's ai where it's
not that useful, people don't like it. but you can see here, for example, this infographic that
we just posted and automated on the live stream today, it's already got 200 views. all right,
so it's already reached 200 new people. all right, now if you reach 200 new people every single
day, would that help you reach more customers? 100. right now, imagine if you 10x out if you
got a virtual system to help you with that. right wouldn't it be powerful? 100. and that's what
we're talking about here. now what i want to do is i want to show you a 30-day plan in terms
of how you can implement this step-by-step into your business. right because really what i want
you to do is just take this stuff and learn it and actually implement it. there's no point just
watching the video about it. take action so that you can see the transformative effects. all
right, so what to do from day 1 to 30, and this is all inside the notes of the ai profit boarding
so. again, you just go into the air profit boarding comes with an amazing community of 1,700
people just like me, interested in ai sharing their latest information. you can also get a calendar
of coaching calls. all right, and if you want to start using this stuff, what you can do is
you can just jump on the coaching course here, jump on the live calls, ask any questions you
have, etc. super simple and easy to do. so if we go back to that 30-day plan, what you're going
to do is just go to the air profit boardroom go to classroom then you're going to scroll down,
and you would go to the sap update section, as you can see. and then inside this, you can see
the link to the, okay, are these actually brand new updates? so you can see here, for example,
this was just announced literally like a couple of days ago, this new slide decks feature. and
what's interesting about this, they've said with slide decks, is less about making slides, more
about telling stories. so this is the official notebook lm website, sorry, account on x and
you can add sources to the storybook, deep research, simplified slides, remove the messy notes,
and basically take all your messy notes and turn it into something amazing, like you can see.
all right, so let's talk about this 30-day plan that we're talking about here. all right, so
i would just go to notebooklm.google.com, assign them with your account, and create your first
notebook. right just test out, upload three to five sources related to something you're working
on right now. generate an audio. if you listen to it, this just gives you an immediate sense
of what's possible. all right, so in terms of a 30-day plan to get results with this stuff,
that's what i would do. day one to day three, in terms of day four to seven, i would build your
first business notebook. all right, so pick one recurring task in your business. maybe it's
creating content, maybe it's client onboarding, maybe it's research, and create a dedicated
notebook for it. okay upload everything related to that task, and that could be old documents,
reference materials, examples you like, and generate a slide deck or infographic from it. and
just see how much time this saves compared to you doing it manually. all right, so for example,
here, let's say, for example, i want to create a new presentation for my team based on a sales
page we've created recently about seo right
SEO. Right could do here. i'm hoping this works. if not, i've got a backup idea. and if it doesn't
work, then that's okay as well. so what we're going to do is we're going to grab this page,
which is our new black friday deal for seo agency. check it out if you want. it's available
at juliangoldie.com if you're interested in ranking on google and llms and so what we're going
to do is we're going to take that url then we're going to go back to notebook.lm. like you can
see, we are going to plug in the websites. we'll just paste in the over here. and then we're
going to use that as training data so that we can create a custom notebook lm based on the information.
as you can see, right? so we've got this notebook lm this is custom trained. now there's a few
different ways that my team could use this, okay, to save me time from training them. so what
else? what could we do here? number one, we could create a slide deck. and inside the slide
deck, we could say, okay create a sales presentation, the client-facing course that sells the
new seo packages we have, plus the black friday deal we have on right now." okay we'll hit generate,
and then that's going to create a custom presentation based on the black friday deal that we
have for seo at the same time, what we can also do is, let's say, for example, i'm training
a new sales rep. he's got questions about how this works. i can share this tool with them. and
then i can go inside here, and i can say, okay give me a, uh, or tell me the 80/20 this deal,
plus what it includes," right? and what that's going to do is dig through the details of the
source we loaded in, which is a web page, right? so this sales page we literally just copied
and pasted in. and then we're going to go back to this tab, and you can see here that we've
got all the details for the 80/20 of this seo package that we're selling for our agency, right?
and so, now we're waiting for the slide deck to generate. we can use that to present back to
our clients once it's done. we can change the style of it. we could even create a video overview,
and with the video view, we could send that to clients, right? and then they can watch that
video breakdown of the sales page. or we could take that video overview, upload it, and then
embed it inside the page and plug it in right here. okay that's another example of how we do.
now taro says, cheers welcome to help." and story box maker. says, if you try it tomorrow, it
will be even better." yeah here is, uh, everything seems to get better, especially notebook
11. like when i was testing this out a year ago, it was already mind-blowing, but now it's even
better. so notebook 11 is crazy powerful, and this stuff just gets better pretty much every
single day. but i think the best time to start using it is now because the thing is, if you
wait, then your competitors are going to start using it. they're going to start learning it.
and if you understand how to use it now, then you've got a much better shot of getting better
results. whereas if you wait, like, you're going to fall behind. people going to start using
this without you, etc. okay so we're waiting for that slide deck to generate, but let's come
back to the 30-day plan. so we've talked about days 4 to 7, which is building your first business
notebook. and then days 8 to 14, you want to really start mastering custom personas. all right,
this is where most people plateau. so inside notebook LM you can just go into your settings,
create a custom persona. tell notebook LM exactly how you want it to respond, what time to use,
what level of detail, what format you prefer. test it with different prompts. refine until it
matches your style. so how do you do that? for example, here you can go to the settings, and
you can add, like, custom. here you can just add a custom example of how you want it to reply,
right? so for example, here, if you wanted, you could actually give this tool to your audience.
train it on whenever you want to teach your audience. and then inside the responses, you could
say, okay every time respond to links to my funnels," right? so let me show an example. up so
people ask questions. every time, answer it, plus transition into pitching booking a call here.
all right, what it's going to do is it's going to pitch our funnel links every time someone
uses it. so it's kind of like a sales tool that works without us having to do anything. so for
example, here, now we can ask a question. okay what happens if rank one is missing?" and then
you can see it's answered the question based on the custom source, which is great. but we were
talking about those custom personas that we're using, right? so for example, here, you can say,
if you're ready to implement this powerful A20 SEO framework with a guarantee, the absolute
best next step is to book a strategy call right now. this will allow us to discuss your specific
goals and how we can secure those page one rankings for you." and boom, it's got a link to our
funnels. all right, and then if we click, it's linked to our funnels right here. beautiful right?
so now it's a sales tool that's working for us, and we can share it to our audience. so pretty
amazing. you can upload this live on youtube to watch it later. so i actually have done that.
if you go to youtube on my live streams here, let me show this tab. so if you go to live, you
can watch back my recordings here. you can see here each day i do like a one to two-hour training
on AI. we do one pretty much every single day, and you can watch them back on youtube there.
all right, so it's pretty simple and easy to do this stuff. if we go back to the 30-day plan,
we've talked about day 1 to 3, which is set up first and win. all right, day 4 to 7, build your
first business notebook. day 8 to 14, master custom personas. all right, day 15 to 21, you want
to build your own content system. okay so create a notebook for your content ideas, and you
can upload articles you want to reference. you could upload transcripts, your own videos. you
could upload notes from your brainstorm. so just use this as a content brain. and then when
you need ideas as well, you could ask the notebook. and when you need to create something, just
generate it from your existing sources. so you can see how quick and easy it is to start building
your own custom content system. days 22 to 28, you can start creating client-ready assets. you
can use what you've learned to create something you can actually use with customers or clients.
that could be a presentation, guide, a training video outline, an infographic explaining your
product process, or something that adds value and looks professional without hours of design
work. and again, that's pretty simple and easy using notebook. and then the final day, i told
you this was a 30-day plan to make sure you can actually implement it into your business. the
final step is you can start documenting what works for you. so you can create templates you
can reuse. share your wins inside the alprofitboarding community. get feedback. help others
who are starting up. this is basically how you solidify your learning. become part of a community
that keeps you sharp, right? as an example of that, we go back to the alprofitboarding here.
we click on wins. you can see all of these different wins right here that people are sharing
right here. so for example, like steve steve just shared a youtube api that uploads from computer
directly to youtube right? pretty crazy. and then he shared how he's done it, and he's actually
shared a pdf right there. pretty crazy. you can see here, for example, we're sharing what we're
grateful for. we actually got 50 ways to be grateful. and i think that's one of the best things
about this community is, yes, we like ai but at the same time, let's enjoy the journey. let's
learn together. let's grow together. let's create something amazing, right? it's not about me.
it's about community and how we can share and learn and grow. also you can see here justin sharing
his heygen avatar and how he made his digital twin based on the tutorials we share inside the
alprofitboarding so you really want to just become part of that community and just share your
wins and systemize, right? the way that i would recommend you really grow is just by finding
people who are doing the same things as you or some people who are doing better things than
you. and then, in terms of prompts, you can see a bunch of prompts you can use right here. and
yeah, that's basically how it if we go back to notebooklmp here, we've still got the slide deck
being built out, and we'll come on to that in a second. but yeah, it's just, it's absolutely
amazing what you can do, what's possible, how powerful this is. and this is a free tool that's
just perfect for people learning about this stuff, people growing with this stuff, right? and
that's what the game is about, my friends. now if you're ready to start using this notebooklmp
if we go back to here, now we've got the presentation. so let's play that back. so you can see
here it's created that sales presentation. if we pull this up, there we go. so this presentation
created with notebooklmp based on that page we just loaded. we've got the details of the black
friday deal, right? and the cool thing about this is my team could easily just use this as a
sales presentation. now you probably want to customize it with your own branding, which you
can do inside notebooklmp as well. but you can see how powerful this is, right? and then it's
even created like the icons. everything's really nicely presented. it's really easy to use.
it's got the problem and the solution, right? so here's the problem. people waste time on audits.
here's our fix. we deliver what matters: content published, links built, rankings tracked, etc.
you can see here, for example, it talks about seo mess, which is a very common problem, right?
we built the system to fix it, which the aico engine. here's what you get inside the package.
here's a simple step-by-step process. and this is all accurate because it's based on our sources.
and then the black friday deal, what you get, etc., right? and this is all generated using notebooklmp
using that simple automation that i've shared with you today. and then we can download that,
or we could just share the link and give clients access to it directly. so for example, here
we could actually switch to anyone with link, hit save, and then if we click on the share button,
copy link slides, we're gonna open that up in a new tab. here we go, link to the slides over
here, right? pretty nice, pretty nice. that is notebooklmp and exactly what you get right here.
and the thing that i would say here is you've seen exactly how notebooklmp works. you've seen
how to turn messy research into slide decks, infographics, and audio content in minutes instead
of hours. but here's the things this is just one single tool, one single update, one piece of
the puzzle, okay? every single week and pretty much every single day now, there's something
new, whether that's a new tool, a new update, new ways to automate what used to take forever.
the question is, how do you keep up, right? how do you know what's worth learning and what's
a waste of time? how do you turn all these tools into actual systems that run your business?
and that's exactly why i built the AI profit boardroom right? if you haven't seen the AI profit
boardroom here it is. this is our community. this is everything that you get. you get a community,
classroom, calendar, etc. the main thing to note here, right, is that i put this together because
i used to be drowning in. every week, i'd spend hours figuring out if it was useful. most of
the time, it actually wasn't. i wasted months on things that didn't move the needle. so i've
started documenting what actually works: the frameworks, the automations, the combinations of
tools that have saved me time. so for example, here you see all these different trainings and
courses. if you've never used AI before, you don't know where to start, you can get that inside
this six-week automation classroom right here. you can also see we have a playbook on all our
best automations for shorts, avatar videos, etc. we even have, for example, all my latest trainings
from november 2025, where i just keep you updated with the frameworks that are working right
now. and basically, how it works, and thing to note here is like we update this every single
day, the latest stuff. i started sharing this stuff first with a few people, then more, and
now we have a community of business owners basically helping each other figure this out together.
and everything i've learned, every shortcut, every system is all right now. here's what you
get when you join the AI Profit Boarding today. number one, you get the AI avatar engine. it
looks something like this, right? so you go to the playbook, and you can see inside here we
have our AI avatar video process. and basically, this is how to duplicate yourself without hiring
anyone. you get automated AI systems that create content, handle delivery, and clone your best
processes. i've spent months building and testing this. i spent thousands of, but the value
of having a virtual team that works around the clock or an AI avatar that publishes youtube
videos for you all day, that's worth so much in terms of save time. you also get unlimited custom
automation requests. so normally, if you wanted someone to build a custom AI workflow, you'd
spend a lot, right? but inside the boardroom, you can request custom automations built specifically
for your business. if you need a workflow that connects your tools or a simple custom gpt you
can do that, right? so let me show an example. that if you go to this thread inside the AI Profit
Boarding, here you can see that we've got this free custom gpts request. inside the AI Profit
Boarding, you can post what you want, and then we create it. so chris requested the lead magnet
custom gpt and then we're like, here you go," his video notes. and then i create a custom video
showing how it works, plus the automation itself. i don't know any other community that's actually
doing that right now. the other thing that i would say here is you get daily live access to
me. so every single day, i go live. you can hop on. you can ask questions. you get coached in
real time. you also get the coaching inside the AI Profit Boarding as well. so if we go back
into the calendar section here, you can jump up the live streams here and just ask any questions
you have live on the course, okay? you get unstuck immediately because instead of spending hours
googling we just help you directly on that call. you don't have to wait for email replies, and
i'm guessing you just get direct help when you need it. you also get the fast track implementation
kit. so this is a copy and paste system so you can start implementing it immediately, right?
this is for people who want momentum right away. so there's no theory, no someday plans, just
actual implementation you can do within 24 hours to join it. so let me show an example. if you
go to the six-week AI automation master class here, you can learn how to build your own AI agent
in under five minutes, right? pretty crazy. and that's inside the AI Profit Boarding. just go
to the classroom and then go to start here as well. and then you also get the black vault, which
is my back-end system. so these are the exact automations behind major client work and deals,
right? so i'm opening this up for people who join during this window during black friday and
this alone took me months to refine. so for example, here, if you go to classroom and then you
go down here to the agency mastermind section, you learn how to land clients, how to grow your
agency. if you want to do more client work, if you're a freelancer, if you're a coach, etc.,
and you need clients, go right here. it shows you how to do sales leads, how to generate content
that actually attracts people into your business, etc. right so you can sign up now during black
friday just click the link below this video or go to the AI Profit Boarding.com. you can choose
between monthly or annual, and you get all the video notes from today as well. so if you go
to the classroom, you get all the video notes for today, plus previous calls, just to get the
coaching call recordings, the Q&A call recording bowl as well. if you go to the SP updates,
you can see this is updated with new video tutorials and step-by-step processes, as you can
see right here. and if you want to indicate how to get the latest stuff, you just go to the
date, right? so november 25th, november 26th, etc. i would just constantly add in new information
and new helpful tutorials inside the AI Profit Boarding.com to help you. all right, muller says
this one is pretty AI. i'm pretty sure this is actually me, but i appreciate that. i must be
quite smooth in presenting, so thank you very. i'll say that as a compliment. but yeah, so you
can see exactly how this works. if you haven't joined the AI Profit Boarding already, make sure
you do join. we've got a 35% off deal right now for black friday
Black Friday. so make sure you sign up. you can lock in your lifetime discount if you sign up
right now. and yeah, no book limit is absolutely amazing. and just to recap on what we've done
today, all right? so if you go back to here, in terms of what we've done, we've talked through
all the new features. so infographics, slide decks, deep research, custom personas, audio reviews,
flashcards and quizzes, video reviews, and how it's free for new users, right? so you can get
access to this stuff. and also, i've talked about my best prompts. and i've shown you the five-step
process to the Goldy Sourced Asset Framework, which is basically sourcing, stacking, shaping,
styling, and sharing. we've also talked about some limiting beliefs and how to avoid them holding
you back, so you can keep growing your business. and finally we've talked about the 30-day plan,
so you can start winning now and implement this for your business, right? and Mullo says, is
it just me or has AI got to the point where it's improving by the second? i would agree with
that. i think it's getting better and better. and i think the slower you are to implement this
stuff into your business, the more you fall behind, right? that's basically it.
Mullo says anticipating grok 5 in q1 january of this year. hopefully it's better than 4.1 because
i was pretty disappointed with that. but yeah, that's basically it, my friends. all right, google
just gave notebook lm superpowers. you can now upload photos of your handwritten notes, textbook
pages, even screenshots, and it reads them like they're typed documents. no more retyping anything
ever again. this is huge, and i'm about to prove it to you live. all right, so here's what just
happened. google rolled out a massive update to notebook lm and it's not just a small tweak.
this thing now accepts images as sources: photos of handwritten notes, textbook pages with diagrams,
screenshots of graphs, whiteboards from your office meetings, all of it. you drag it in, and
notebook lm reads it. it runs something called ocr which means optical character recognition.
that's just a fancy way of saying it looks at your photo and extracts all the text and meaning
from it. that you can ask it questions about what's in the image, like you're talking to someone
who just read your notes for you. let me show you why this matters. you know how you take a
photo of notes in class or at a meeting, or you screenshot something important from a website?
most people never look at those photos again. they just sit in your camera roll, collecting
digital dust. now you can upload those into notebook lm and actually use them. you can ask questions
like, what were the three main points from this meeting? or explain this graph to me in simple
terms. and notebook lm will answer based on what it sees in your image. it's like having a research
assistant who never sleeps and never complains. but here's where it gets even better. notebook
lm also added something called deep research and discover. these tools can automatically find
web sources for you, so you're not just limited to what you upload. you can tell notebook lm
to go find additional information on a topic, and it will pull articles, studies, and data from
across the web. then it combines everything: your uploads and the web sources into one big research
notebook, all in one place. no more juggling 10 browser tabs and three different note apps.
now let me walk you through exactly how this works. first you open notebook lm you create a
new notebook. then you drag in your images. let's say you have a photo of handwritten notes
from a lecture. you drop it into the sources panel. notebook lm processes it for a few seconds.
then boom, it shows up as a source you can reference. now you go to the chat and ask a question,
something like summarize the key points from my handwritten notes. notebook lm reads the image,
extracts the text, and gives you a clean summary. now okay, this is cool, but how do i take
this to the next level and actually scale my business with ai i want to tell you about the ai
profit boardroom this. is the best place to scale your business, get more customers, and save
hundreds of hours with ai automation. inside you'll find a community of entrepreneurs and business
owners who are using ai to grow faster and work smarter. we share case studies, tools, workflows,
and strategies that actually work. if you're serious about using ai to build your business,
you need to be in there. i'll drop the link in the description. check it out. all right, back
to notebook lm but it doesn't stop there. you can ask follow-up questions like, what did i write
about marketing strategies? or which section talked about customer retention? and it pulls the
exact info from your photo. let me give you a real example. say you photographed a textbook
page with a complex diagram. you upload it, then you ask, explain this diagram in simple terms.
notebook lm looks at the image, understands the visual layout, reads any labels or text, and
explains it back to you like you hired a tutor who can see what you're looking at. or imagine
you screenshot a graph from a research report. you upload it and ask, what's the shown in this
graph? notebook lm analyzes the data points, the axis, the legend, and tells you what the graph
is saying. no manual data entry, no squinting at tiny text, just instant analysis. now here's
the part that makes this a total game changer. you can mix image uploads with other source types:
pdfs, google docs, google sheets. even urls all in the same notebook. so you could have a photo
of your meeting notes, a pdf of a research paper, a google sheet with your data, and a few web
articles. notebook lm treats them all as sources and can answer questions that pull from any
of them. it's like building your own personal knowledge base. and the new discover and deep
research tools make it even more powerful. let's say you're researching a topic, but you don't
have all the sources yet. you can tell notebook lm to use deep research. it goes out and finds
relevant articles, studies, and data for you. then it adds those as sources to your notebook
automatically. you don't have to hunt down links or copy-paste urls notebook lm does the heavy
lifting. then you can ask questions that combine everything: your uploads and the web sources
it found. it's like having a research team working for you around the clock. but i need to be
real with you about the limitations because no tool is perfect. and if you don't know the weak
spots, you're going to get burned. first ocr is good, but magic if your handwriting is messy.
the accuracy drops. if your photo is blurry or the lighting is bad, is going to miss stuff.
so always double-check what it extracted. compare the image side by side with what notebook
lm says it found. don't just trust it blindly. second there are upload limits. you can't just
dump a thousand images into one notebook. google has caps on the number of sources and the file
sizes. so if you're working on a massive project, you might need multiple notebooks. third some
features are still english only, like the audio overview feature where notebook lm generates
a spoken summary. if your content is in another language, that feature won't work yet. now let's
talk about privacy. this is important. when you upload an image, notebook lm processes it in
the cloud. the that means google sees it. if you're uploading sensitive information like medical
records or confidential business documents, you need to be careful. you might want to redact
names, account numbers, or anything private before you upload, or just avoid uploading it until
notebook lm offers local processing options. right now, everything goes through google servers,
so treat it the way you treat any cloud service. if you wouldn't put it in google drive don't
put it in notebook lm all right, so how do you get the best results with this image feature?
here are my tips. number one, take clean photos. shoot straight on, not at an angle. make sure
the lighting is bright and even, no shadows across the page. the cleaner your image, the better
the ocr number two, use high resolution. don't upload a tiny compressed screenshot. if you can,
use the original photo or a high-quality scan. more pixels means better text recognition. number
three, test it first. upload a sample image and see what notebook lm extracts. if it's missing
words or getting things wrong, retake the photo with better conditions. number four, verify
the output. always check the original image against what notebook lm says, especially for numbers,
dates, or critical facts. ocr can misread similar-looking characters like an eight and a capital
b or a zero and the letter o if you're using this for something important, you have to verify.
now here's something cool you can do with this. you can build a personal research library. every
time you read a book, take photos of the you print out notes from meetings, whiteboard sessions,
anything. over time, you'll have this massive searchable database of everything you've learned.
and you can ask notebook lm to pull ideas from across all your sources, like show me everything
i've learned about email marketing from all my sources, or what are the common themes in my
meeting notes from the last three months. it's like giving yourself a photographic memory, but
better because you can search and analyze it. another use case: students can photograph their
class notes and textbooks, then use notebook lm to quiz themselves or generate study guides.
instead of rereading 100 pages, you ask questions and get targeted answers. freelancers and
consultants can use it to organize client research. upload notes from discovery calls, screenshots
of competitor websites, pdfs of industry reports, then ask notebook lm to find patterns or create
summaries for your client presentations. content creators can it to gather research for videos,
articles, or courses. take photos of books, upload pdfs add web sources, and let notebook lm
help you outline your content. the possibilities are kind of endless. but here's the thing:
this tool is only as good as the sources you give it. if you upload garbage, you get garbage
out. so be intentional about what you add and always fact-check. notebook lm can summarize and
cite, but it can also get things wrong, especially if the source itself is wrong or if the ocr
misreads something. so use it as a starting point, not the final answer. now let me hit you
with one more feature that ties this all together. the discover tool doesn't just find random
articles. it actually tries to find sources that are relevant to the question you're asking
or the topic you're researching. so if you're writing a paper on climate change and you've uploaded
some notes, you can tell notebook lm to discover more sources. it will go find scientific studies,
news articles, and expert opinions. then it adds them to your notebook, and you can ask questions
that pull from all of them. it's like having a librarian who knows exactly what you need before
you even ask. and because everything is in one notebook, you're not switching between apps or
losing track of where you found something. all your sources are right there. you can see them
in the sources panel. you can click on any source to read the full text or view the original
image. and when notebook lm. gives you an answer, it cites which source it pulled from, so you
can trace every claim back to the original. that's huge for credibility, especially if you're
doing research for work or school. use it to build a personal research library, create study
materials, organize client work, or gather content research. start small, be consistent, and
let the tool do the heavy lifting. that's everything you need to know. now go try upload an
image, ask a question, see what notebook lm can do. and here's what i want you to do: drop a
comment below and tell me what kind of image you're going to test first. handwritten notes,
a textbook page, screenshot? i want to know. julian goldie reads every comment, so make sure
you comment below. today we're going to be running through the latest updates from notebook
lm so, notebook lm have. released three new big updates today. one of them is the deep research
update. this literally just been announced a few hours ago, as you can see. and they've said
rolling out now, deep research browses hundreds of sites to craft an organized report and give
you an annotated list of sources for deeper exploration, all of which you can add directly to
your notebook. so that is update number one. we also have update number two, where they've said
finally the moment you've been waiting for, rolling out today, you can now create your own custom
video overview styles by tapping the prompt in the customization box. drop your favorite examples,
blah blah blah. we also have another update which says chat history is rolling out now, so you
can actually close the resume it later without losing your conversation, which is another new
update on notebook lm now if you've never used notebook lm before, it's a really powerful and
free tool that you can use to generate outputs like you can see right here, right? and you can
use this to generate like videos, podcasts. you can create some really powerful tools, kind
of like custom trained on whatever you want, essentially. and i'm going to show you exactly
how to use this. all right, so if we go to create new, we're going to test out the deep research
mode first. we can use deep research mode here inside notebook lm so let's have a look here,
and we'll test this out. so you can see we've got this try deep research for an in-depth report
on new sources, and you've got an option between deep research and fast research, right? so
fast research was the old option where you could pretty much just quickly get answers and search
and that sort of thing. now deep research is where you can get more in-depth reports, and then
you can use those to create audio or to create videos or to create mind maps or reports or flashcards
or quizzes, right? so we can go over here, and we shall say, okay, research do deep research
and the latest ai updates this week, right? just as an example, you can change this prompt to
whatever you want, but we're going to just use that as a basic example for exploring degrees.
nicolas says it's the essential ai tool. it is indeed, my friends. i think out of everything
that i've tested, honestly, like, um, is miles ahead of 99% of the stuff i've tested. i've put
like thousands of hours into this, right? so if you've never tried notebook lm before, definitely
check it out. whilst we're waiting for the deep research mode to run, i'm going to open up a
new tab, and i'll show you some of the other examples that we do. for example, here we have
the deep research running, and then if we this tab instead, you can see some examples of what
i created previously. for example, here we've loaded up a bunch of sources into our content,
and then we can use this kind of custom train tool to answer any questions that we have. but
also, we can automate audio overviews, video views, mind maps, etc. so it's really easy to use,
quite simple. and the next option that we have is the custom video overview styles, right? so
if we go to video overview here, and then we click on edit based on the sources that we have
on the left-hand side, we can start using this for video views, right? so we choose our language,
like you can see you can get all sorts of languages down here on the left-hand side. and then
you can choose what sort of visual style you want. now you can actually click on custom here,
and you can type what the visual style is that you want for your particular presentation. so
if we open this up, you've got, for example, whiteboard style, anime, or heritage, or watercolor,
or paper craft, or retro print, right? all these. and now, you can, so if you've got a certain
style in mind, or even like a certain artist that you want to use for this, you can use it inside
notebook lm like you can see just by going to the video overview and then describing what you
want as a prompt. so we'll try that in a second here. you could also, for example, try 8-bit
pixelated, and then you can see like this really interesting video view style, pop art, hyper-realistic,
and super cute or super weird, like surreal. so let's go over here. we'll try this out. so i'm
going to say, okay, super weird style. in fact, you know what? i'm going to take a screenshot
here, and then we go over to chat gpt and i'm pasting that screenshot, and i'll say, okay. come
up with some ideas of notebook llm styles, visual styles for a video i'll create. and that should
give me some ideas personalized to me that i can use to start creating these videos. nicolas
says, oh that's a nice addition to have video styles. just wish it would do british english
rather than american english voices." hopefully that's coming out soon. i know they've just
released a bunch of new updates to ai studio where you can essentially plug in different voices.
some of them are much more realistic than previous, so that's something really cool. and i think
that'll come to notebook lm too pretty soon. all right, so it's giving us some ideas here. so
for example, hyper neon cyber lab. let's try that. if we go to video overview style, add a custom.
you can also auto select, so if you're not sure what to use but you want some ideas, you can
always just select auto select instead if you want. i'm going to go with custom, and we'll try
this out. so i'm gonna say hyper neon cyber lab. and then we can give it a specific use case.
so we could say, okay present this to a book club" or help me review for a quiz" or focus on
a specific source." right you can also describe the show structure. right so now i'm going to
say, okay give me some ideas on this for a presentation about plexi seo i'll go back to chat
gpt and the tab here. we'll plug in the screenshot. i said, give me some actual real use cases
for a video i can create about plexi ai2o and there we go. it's giving us some ideas here. i'm
going to say, okay be more in depth in the instructions." so this video is amazing, plus very
well thought out. there we go. all right, for ai seo workflow breakdown using plexi we'll copy
that. we'll go back to notebook lm the cool thing about this is you can do it really quickly
and on the spot. right so if you need inspiration but you want it personalized to you and you
don't want anything generic, then you can use chat gpt and a combination of notebook lm to help
you. right we're going to say, okay for a seo breakdown using plexi walk viewers step by step
through a complete ai powered seo workflow." begin by identifying low competition keywords.
set up intent. move into creating topic clusters, etc. right and i'll say, yeah that's simplified,
plus make it very practical." okay so we've got hyper neon cyber lab. we've got these instructions
right here. i want to say target audience equals entrepreneurs on youtube learning about ai
seo we'll hit generate. now it's going to generate that video overview based on the we gave
it. so just to recap here, the two changes that we've walked you through so far. number one,
deep research. so you can use deep research to generate outputs like you can see over here.
now the deep research is completed. we can see the research over here. so this is the full research
report, and then it's also included all the cited sources. so it's automatically loaded 27 sources
inside our content that we can use to generate this deep research report. now here's the interesting
thing. we've got a custom trained ai tool that you can create for free that's trained on the
deep research you've just come up with, which is super powerful. because now the quality of
your outputs on notebook lm depend on the quality of sources you load in and the research that
you train it on. right why is that important? it's important because now you've got a custom
gpt or a notebook lm very similar things that are custom trained on some of the best research
you could possibly get on that particular topic. right so you can see here that it's loaded
up all the sources, all the information, etc. and we're going to click on import, and that's
going to import all of those sources automatically straight into notebook and then we can use
the chat here, and we can use the audio and video overview with custom styles to generate our
report. so you can see here the untitled notebook. we can easily change the name of that, and
you can switch it between default, learning guide, or custom. and you can choose your response
length, so longer, shorter, etc. and then if you were trying to say keep up with the latest
ai updates in your industry, you just go down here, start typing, say, okay tell me about the
new updates this week in ai and now you will never fall behind. now obviously, there are so
many different tools you could build with this, but this is just one example. for example, i
previously created a sales trainer that trains my team. they can ask any questions inside the
notebook lm based on my step-by-step instructions and guide for selling. and then they can go
inside here and ask questions. right and so you can build a custom ai tool very quickly about
almost anything that you can think of. it will give you the updates. right so for example here,
what's happened recently? so it says the updates this week in ai are marked by a critical convergence
of all this sort of crazy stuff that's going on. so for example, like autonomous cyber risk
or guardrail evasion. we've got frontier models. right so for example, like badu journey 5 0.
that literally just came out recently. right i've also got this for all these pieces of information
too. now this is important too because when i know the ai hallucinates and tends to make up
a lot of stuff. right, and, so, if you can easily bypass that by creating this sort of content,
then you're gonna get much better results. right the quality of the results you get from all
this information is going to be much better because it's based on more accurate data, and it's
only using the sources that you've custom trained it on, which is great. it's going to save
you a lot of time. save you a... so for example, also it's talked about claude's 4 5 split and
the dominance there. open source efficiency that's just improved. some new regulations it just
came into place, and also the custom ai chip that just came out. right so that just came out
on november the 14th, and we've also got information about all the latest improvements in the
industry there. and it said to illustrate the change in irs this week, but here's some examples.
right now how do we use this information? so we use it inside the chat here, and we can also
simplify the responses. so if you actually have a look here, like this is not the nicest formatted
way to receive information, honestly. so i would just change the examples here and just change
the style and tone to be simpler and easier to understand. right so we could say, okay beautiful
formatting, easy to understand, add nice emojis, reply simply, make it super practical, and
explain why these updates are important." and then also simplify the responses to be third grade
language. now if you want longer responses, you can select there. if you want shorter responses,
you can go there. but i'm just going to go with the default here. right and then if we hit save,
we'll say, okay tell me about the new updates this week." wait for that. so now it's using the
custom instructions to create the answer. right now have a look at these responses, which are
like super messy, quite difficult to read, not that fun to interact with. and compare it to
this one, right? where it's got nice headers, it's simplified the language. anyone can read
that and understand what's going on. and then it also summarizes the updates. it's update three,
update four, right? update five. so super easy to do. and then from here, we can then start
generating an audio view based on what's happened. right now inside the audio view here, which
is basically like generating a podcast with two different people, you can also select the language
here. so you can create this in german or whatever. you can change it to be short, long, or
default. and then you can also switch between what you want to talk about. for example, it could
be deep dive or brief or critique or debate. and then inside this section, you've got the, what
should the ai host focus on?" right so you can say, okay focus only on the new ai tool updates.
summarize them so anyone can understand the latest ai updates this week." we'll select sure.
that's going to make it quicker to generate, also easier to use. and say simplify the language
so it's fair grade. and then if you want to create a podcast, maybe to embed inside a blog or
inside your website or share on social media or create on youtube then the way that you do this
is you'd also say, okay let's say you've got a product and you want to use this commercially."
right you could say, okay subtly sell the benefits of the profit bordering," and you replace
this with whatever you want to sell. available and we'll put available at aiprofitbordering.com
and mention this is the best ai automation community that learn ai automation, get coaching,
ai coaching and support, plus connect with an amazing community of people. and so now this is
a very practical use case because we've got a tool that can generate videos, audio views. it
creates them exactly how we want them to be. we can change the length and the response and the
style of the language. and then we can also use that as a sales tool for our business so that
we can generate and sell whatever we want to do. so if we hit generate, so that's now going
to generate an audio overview, which we can come back to in a minute. it's pretty simple and
easy to do. right doesn't take a long time at all. we've got the deep research report ready
here. it has failed to bring in a few, so you can see here is actually failed to bring this
in. says invalid url but that's okay because we've got so many resources from the deep research
report. we can use those to generate more, and it doesn't really matter if some of them don't
work. we're playing the numbers game, and we're generating so many inputs. so that's the deep
research. that's how to generate the audio views based on exactly what we want. we've got the
video overview as well, but still generating, so that might take about five, ten, twenty minutes
to generate. actually when we come to video views, the final update that we have is the chat
history. right so you can close the session and resume it later. how do you do that? let me
show you. so if we go back to notebook lm over here, we've got a bunch of options. right so
for example, we've got my notebooks, featured notebooks, shared with me, and then we should
be able to come back to history. now when i actually check notebook lm i can't see this option
inside notebook lm so it's just something to be aware of. maybe it's still rolling out. you
can see it as chat history is rolling out now, so maybe that's coming to more people later.
i actually can't see it, to be honest with you, but that should appear inside the history here.
let's have a look inside notebook lm if we actually click off that, and then we go back to the
notebook lm you can actually see the history inside the chat here, which is great. so basically
what that new update is allowed is all the interactions that you have with the ai it actually
saves, and then you can see the previous responses. right you can come back to those and search
through them and find previous options. whereas normally, if you came back to a notebook lm
like you've created here, it would start from scratch. right you wouldn't have any history on
that. i wonder if that's tracked it for old ones as well. so let's have a look here. we'll have
a look at this one. yeah so you see how it's not got any information or previous responses.
let's have a look at this one. yeah so you can see it's not saving the old chat history. it's
just for the new ones it creates, if that makes sense. a pretty cool update. lots of cool stuff
right there. seems really easy to use as well. and then we've got some other cool stuff here.
now at the top, you also got featured notebooks, so you can check out all this stuff. but you've
also got the notebooks that you've created. right so this is like all of the notebooks, including
the featured ones. but you can switch to my notebooks, and then you can see all of these previous
notebooks that we've created. so for example, we've got the account managers growth playbook.
we have the advanced sales operating procedure notebook, lm, right, so. this is the tool that
i was talking about before that we use to actually train our team. now if we go to one of these
videos on the right, these were old videos i've generated, but they're still pretty cool. so
for example, if i click on this one, i won't play the sound back because it probably doesn't
sound good on the live stream. but we can play. today we're gonna do something a little different.
we got our hands on an actual internal textbook theory. okay it's the question every single
sales leader on the planet wants to answer. and well the answer might not be what you think.
here's the thing. according to this playbook, the secret isn't some clever script or fancy new
piece of software. it all starts with a very specific and frankly an incredibly intense philosophy.
this is the engine that makes the whole thing go. and just to be clear, this isn't some motivational
poster on the wall. no the document makes one thing crystal clear. this number is the... now
we have our explainer video ready to go as well. so if we go back to our explainer video, we
have this ready on the right-hand side over here. so let's play that back now. so open this
up. this is a custom style video that... all right, let's get right into it. let's listen to
this. all right, let's get right into it. today we are breaking down a complete practical ai
seo workflow that is built from the ground up for solopreneurs. seriously this isn't just theory.
it's a system you can actually use to start ranking and getting traffic in this totally new
era of search, all by using tools like perplexity. and you know what? that is not an exaggeration.
the stuff we're about to cover is so new it gives you a massive advantage. while everybody else
is out there fighting the old seo war, you're about to learn the rules to a whole new game.
so that's using that cyber robot ai style that we asked it to do with the neon style. so you
can see that in the background here, and it's created a really nice hook, but it's very simplified.
right so it's okay. 99% of your competitors have no clue. it almost feels like a bsl or a video
sales letter that's selling that process, keeping people interested. we've generated the whole
video, and what i think it's taken about 20-25 minutes to run through. so let's keep going through.
and if you're wondering, does this stuff actually work? just look at this number. this is real
traffic to a real site that went from absolutely nothing to 87,000 visitors in just a few days.
how by using one specific feature in perplexity. this is the kind of wild growth that's suddenly
possible. so let's set the stage here. to win today, you have to get your head around the fact
that the entire... i actually don't, i don't like that style that much, but i think it is cool
to test it out and see what it's like. and i think you could have a lot of plays around with
that. right you could you could mess around, and then once you finally find something that you
like, you can save the preset and come back to it later. so let's keep playing. now foundation
of seo is shifting like right now, right under our feet. okay let's break this down. think about
it. old and then it talks about the old way and the new way as well. right so here's the old
style of seo here's a new way of seo so it's really cool. all of these slides were automated.
the style was custom preset to what we want. the content itself is optimized to exactly how
we wanted it. it's a six-minute video, very in-depth, very easy to understand, nicely narrated.
i don't think it's mentioned that our profit volume is... that's the only issue that would...
a whole cluster of articles around one topic makes... see that? but it's still pretty good.
and then you can show the prompt here. this you can see the example right here of the content
that we've created. and then we also have the audio overview over here. so this is the podcast
will be generated with the new ai updates. so let's play this one back. welcome our mission
today is a fast, clear deep dive into the absolute must-know ai tool updates this week. we've
sifted through all the research and news articles to pull out what really matters for you. and
it's moving so fast, almost impossible to keep up. it really is. so we're going to... simple
so this is the one based on deep research. as you can see, we've got the sources on the left.
we've got custom notebook lm inside here, and then we have the podcast over here. right now
this is actually interactive as well. so we could go inside here, and in interactive mode, we
can actually interact with the podcast itself and ask any questions. so let's play it. welcome
our mission today is a fast, clear deep dive into the absolute must-know ai tool updates this
week. we've sifted through all the research and news articles to pull out what really matters
for you. and it is moving so fast. hey our listener wants to join in. what's up? hey so i wanted
to ask, what are the new updates this week? could you summarize them in 10 to 20 words? oh that's
a great question. you want the whole thing in a tight nutshell? let's unpack this quick summary.
absolutely the biggest updates are new omnimodal models, ernie 5 0 agents are taking over 90%
of cyber attacks, plus custom ai chips and california's new frontier model regulation. that's
the core. so you can see here how you can actually interact. ask questions with your microphone.
talk to the ai ask it for exactly what you want, and then it'll get back to you straight away.
so there's some really cool stuff right there. just to recap, you've got deep research ready
to go. you have the custom video overviews generated as well. and then you have the chat history
rolling out now too. so you can see how easy it is to use. lots of powerful stuff. loads of different use cases.
Pablo says impressed, so I'm glad that video helped you and the updates helped you. but yeah,
it's really cool what you can do, and there's so many different options for that. and basically
inside this community, it's a free community where you can join and interact with 36,700 members.
with loads of cool updates, always being lots of active community in there. you can all see
inside the classroom here. you can learn loads of different stuff about AI. so for example,
you've got all these different trainings on AI agents, 3, Haygen, etc.
Manus loads of cool stuff on AI super agents, and we're updating this all the time. so this
is a free community you can join. link in the comments description if you want to get help on
this stuff. and also if you want to get help, support, coaching directly with me, join the AI
Profit Boardroom. inside the AI Profit Boardroom community, we have a really active community
of 1,700 AI builders. so some really amazing people inside there. you see how active that is.
loads of people like sharing their wins and what's working and what's not, etc. so you can see
the win section here. the goal for this community is for everyone just to learn and grow and
help each other learn about. inside the classroom, as well, we have all of my best automations,
including a six-week AI automation masterclass. so if you're interested in learning about AI,
how to go from zero to building your first AI agent in under five minutes, you can. and then
additionally, inside here as well, if you want to learn more about, say, notebook 11, you can
just type in notebook 11. and we have all these different custom trainings with video tutorials
and step-by-step instructions on exactly how to use them. if you love like AI video stuff as
well, you can type in video, and you can see all these different automations here on different
stuff that you can do with AI. so feel free to get that link in the comments to the AI Profit
Boardroom. it also comes with five weekly coaching calls as well. so if you go to the calendar
here, you can see all the coaching calls. you can join these and ask for help and advice, and
etc. if you can't make the coaching calls, no problem. you can actually watch them back inside
the coaching course section here. so some amazing stuff inside the new notebook LM updates.
and also if you want to get help on just implementing this yourself for your business, then
feel free to book in an AI automation session. and on that call, we can basically look at your
business, all your time, figure out what you need to automate, and then go off and automate
it for you. right so that's a full process right there. this free tool just changed everything for SEO content.
I'm about to show you how to turn a couple PDFs into a video-making machine. and there's one
hidden trick at the end that's gonna blow your mind. this works for any niche, and it takes
like 10 minutes to set up. let's go. so here's what's wild about notebook LM. it's completely free.
Google made it, and nobody's talking about the SEO angle. everyone's using it for research,
but I'm gonna show you how to use it to steal traffic and rank videos faster than ever before.
this tool does something crazy. you upload a few files. could be PDFs, could be Google Docs,
could be blog posts, and it gives you everything you need for a video: the script, the keywords,
the chapters, even the slides, all from those files.
I'm gonna walk you through this step by step using a real example, so you can copy this exact
process. and here's the thing: this isn't some complicated workflow. it's literally seven prompts.
that's it. seven prompts, and you go from random documents to a complete video ready to upload.
I'm using fitness content as my example today, but this works for anything: real estate, SaaS,
ecommerce, coaching, doesn't matter. first thing you need to do is prep your files. this is
step zero. go find two or three sources about your topic. for me, I grabbed a PDF called beginner
fitness plan. then I found a blog post about seven-day home workouts, and I added a Google Doc
with nutrition basics. that's it. three simple sources. now here's why this matters. notebook
LM works best when you give it a focused content, not hundred random files. just two or three
good ones that cover your topic. this keeps the output tight and relevant. now you're going
to create a notebook in notebook LM and upload those files. super easy. just drag and drop.
once they're in, you're gonna use your first prompt, and this prompt sets up everything that
comes after. here's what you say: you are my research assistant.
I uploaded three sources about a beginner fitness plan. give me a concise three-paragraph summary
that highlights the goal for a four-week beginner fitness plan, seven proven exercise types
to include, and five nutrition do's and don'ts. use bullet points for the exercise types and
nutrition tips. that's it. hit enter, and notebook LM gives you this beautiful summary: clean,
organized, ready to work with. and if you want our team to help you scale this even further,
we're offering free SEO strategy sessions. and I mean actually free, no catch, no pressure.
we'll jump on a call with you and show you exactly how to use systems like this to grow your
business. we'll look at your specific situation, your niche, your competition, and we'll map
out a plan that works for you. real strategies, real tactics, the same stuff we use with our
paying clients. no pitch, no sales nonsense, just value. because we know if we help you get
results, you'll remember us. the link is in the comments and description. now here's where it
gets good. you're going to extract SEO keywords from that summary. this is prompt 2, and it's
going to give you everything you need for YouTube. here's the prompt: using your summary above,
extract 30 SEO keywords and group them by intent: informational, commercial, and navigational.
make the suggestions targeted to beginners searching about fitness plan for beginners and mark
the top 7 as priority keywords. also suggest six short clickable YouTube title variants that
include at least one top keyword. boom notebook LM spits out 30 keywords organized by intent.
plus it gives you six ready-to-use titles. this is insane because you're not guessing anymore.
the keywords come straight from your content, so they're relevant, they're natural, and they're
going to help you rank. but wait, it gets better. now you're going to turn those keywords into
a full video script. this is prompt 3, and this is where notebook LM becomes your writer. here's
what you say: I using the top 7 priority keywords you chose, write a punchy 4-minute video script
with a 7-second hook, three short bullets for the first minute, demo one mini case example for
a 21-year-old beginner, and a 15-second CTA. include on screen text cues and suggest six chapter
titles for YouTube timestamps. keep sentences short and energetic. and just like that, you have
a script with a hook, with timestamps, with examples, everything you need to record. no more
staring at a blank page. no more writer's block. just copy the script and start filming. now
here's the part that blew my mind. notebook LM has this feature called video overview, and most
people don't even know it exists. but this is a game changer. you can actually create a narrated
slideshow inside notebook LM and then export it. so his prompt: for create a video overview
from the notebook title problem: four-week plan split into weeks and goals, seven core exercises
itemized, sample meal plan, and CTA for each slide. provide a 10 to 20-second narration and
suggested visual, like an image or diagram or short clip, and list three royalty-free image
keywords to use. notebook LM builds the whole thing for you: slides, narration, even tells you
what images to find. you can literally use this as your video or use it as b-roll or turn it
into shorts. the options are endless. alright so you've got your script, you've got your slides.
now you need to optimize for YouTube. this is where most people drop the ball. they make great
content, but nobody finds it. not you. you're going to use prompt 5, and this gives you all
the metadata you need. is the prompt: from the video script and the top priority keywords, write
a 100-character clickbait but accurate title, a compelling 150-word YouTube description that
includes three priority keywords in the first 50 words, 15 tags, comma-separated, and 6 timestamp
chapter lines. make the description short, punchy, and include a CTA to the pinned comment where
the notebook LM links are. copy this into your YouTube upload: title, description, tags, chapters.
everything is done, and it's all SEO optimized because it came from your content and your keywords.
now we're going to talk about the real hack, the thing nobody's doing. you're going to repurpose
this into shorts. this is prompt 6, and this is how you 10x your reach. here's what you say:
create three 60-second short scripts, each with an opening line, three quick facts from the
video, and a one-line CTA. then write six Instagram and Twitter captions, one sentence each,
punchy, each including one of the priority keywords and an emoji. keep captions line broken
and snappy. now you've got three shorts, six social posts, all from the same content. and here's
what happens: the shorts drive traffic to the main video. the social posts drive traffic to
the shorts. everything feeds everything else. this is how you dominate the topic. but we're
not done yet. there's one more prompt, and this one is for the SEO nerds. prompt 7: produce
a full transcript cleaned and extract the top 10 people also our style questions with one sentence
answers. we can put in the pinned comment and description for SEO. this does two things. first
the transcript helps YouTube understand your video better. understanding means better rankings.
second those 10 questions go in your pinned comment, and when people search those questions,
your video shows up. this is free traffic from people actively looking for answers, and you
just gave YouTube exactly what it needs to rank you. so here's my challenge to you: go try this
today. pick one topic, run through the seven prompts, make one video, and then come back and
tell me how it went. drop a comment below. tell me what worked, tell me what didn't, tell me
what you learned because this is just the beginning. notebook LM is going to keep getting better.
AI tools are going to keep getting better, and the people who learn how to use them are going
to dominate. so get in now, test it, break it, figure out what works for your niche, and then
scale it because this is the future of content creation, and you're either in or you're out.
and if you want our team to help you scale this even further, we're offering free SEO strategy
sessions. and I mean actually free, no catch, no pressure. we'll jump on a call with you and
show you exactly how to use systems like this to grow your business. we'll look at your specific
situation, your niche, your competition, and we'll map out a plan that works for you. real strategies,
real tactics, the same stuff we use with our paying clients. no pitch, no sales nonsense, just
value because we know if we help you get results, you'll remember us. the link is in the comments
and description. if you want to go even deeper with AI and SEO, join SEO elite circle. rank
number one, get more customers, and steal the exact systems we're using to scale past eight
figures. this is where I share everything: the strategies, the tools, the workflows, the stuff
that's actually working right now, not theory, not fluff.
Google just dropped something wild. notebook LM now shows math like a textbook. no more messy
code. this is the update students have been begging for. notebook LM just added native latex
rendering, and if you don't know what that means, stick with me because this is huge for anyone
studying math, science, engineering, or anything with equations. before this update, if you
tried to study math in notebook LM, you'd see ugly code like backslash int underscore a to the
power of B dollar signs everywhere. it looked like a computer threw up on your screen. you couldn't
read it, you couldn't study from it, it was a mess. now everything changed. those same equations
show up clean, beautiful, just like they do in your textbook. we're talking proper fractions,
integrals that actually look like integrals, quadratic formulas that make sense. this works
in chat, flashcards, and quizzes, all of them native support across the board. and here's why
this matters: when you're studying for an exam, the last thing you need is to decode what your
notes mean. you need clear equations. you need to see the math the way it's supposed to look,
and now notebook LM does that automatically. upload your notes, and boom! let me show you how
this actually works in practice. you take your messy math notes, the ones with all the raw latex
code, and you paste them into notebook LM. maybe it's an integral, maybe it's a complex formula,
doesn't matter. notebook LM reads it and displays it perfectly. no guessing, no squinting, just
clean readable math that you can actually study from. but here's where it gets really good:
the flashcards. this is the game changer. you upload a PDF or your type notes that have equations
in them. then you tell notebook LM to generate flashcards, and what you get back are study cards
with perfectly formatted equations. front of the card has a question, back has the answer with
the formula looking exactly like it should. no more raw code, no more confusion. same thing
with quizzes. you can generate practice questions from your notes, and if those questions involve
math, the equations show up clean. this means you can actually test yourself properly. you see
a question with a nice equation, you solve it, you check your answer. everything flows the way
studying should flow. now if you want to take this even further and learn how to use AI to actually
scale your business, get more customers, and save hundreds of hours with automation, you need
to join my AI profit boardroom. this is where I show you exactly how to use tools like notebook
LM and dozens of other AI platforms to build real systems. we're talking lead generation, customer
service, content creation, all automated with AI. this isn't theory. this is stuff my agency
uses every single day to serve clients. so back at it. this isn't just about looking pretty.
this is about fewer mistakes. and when you're studying and you see a messy equation, you might
copy it wrong. you might miss a subscript. you might read a variable incorrectly. but when the
math is rendered properly, you see exactly what you need to see. your brain processes it faster.
you make fewer errors. your study sessions become way more effective. so back at it. teachers
love this too. if you're an educator, you can now share study sets with your students that actually
look professional. no more apologizing for the formatting. no more saying ignore the dollar
signs. you just share clean content that students can actually use. and for test prep, this
is huge. formulas appear in your flashcards exactly like they appear in textbooks. so when you
sit down for your exam, nothing looks unfamiliar. you've been studying with properly formatted
equations the whole time. your brain recognizes everything instantly. now let me give you some
practical tips because there are a few things you need to know to get the most out of this.
first there's a difference between inline math and display math. inline math is when you have
a small equation in the middle of a sentence, like X squared. display math is when you have
a big formula on its own line, like a long integral. notebook LM handles both, but knowing this
helps you format your flashcards better. if you have a long formula, give it space. let it display
properly. second tip: if you have older notebooks in notebook LM from before this update, they
might still show the fix. is simple: just reupload your notes or rerun the flashcard generation.
that's it. notebook LM will process them with the new rendering, and everything will look clean.
third thing you should know before this update, some people were using community scripts and
browser extensions to fake latex rendering. they had to install extra stuff just to make their
math readable. now you don't need any of that. it's all native. it's all built in. google did
it properly. so if you're using those workarounds, you can drop them now. let me give you some
real use cases because this opens up so many possibilities. say you're studying calculus. you
can make a study pack with 30 flashcards covering integration basics. each card has clean integrals,
limits, derivatives. you go through them. you drill the concepts. everything looks professional.
or maybe you have a midterm coming up. you take your lecture notes, upload them to notebook
LM, and generate a 10-question practice quiz. every question with math in it displays perfectly.
you take the quiz, you see where you're weak, you go back and study those areas. it's a complete
study system now. and here's something cool. notebook LM also does audio overviews for some
content. so you could potentially generate flashcards with equations, study them visually, then
listen to an audio overview of the core concepts. it's all connected. it's a full learning ecosystem
now, not just a note-taking tool. this update is part of a bigger push google made in fall 2025.
they've been expanding notebook LM's study features across the board: flashcards, quizzes, video
support, audio support, and now latex rendering fits right into that toolset. it's not just
one feature in isolation. it's part of making notebook LM a serious study platform. and the
community has been asking for this forever. if you go on reddit or twitter students have been
begging for math rendering in notebook LM. people were sharing workarounds, writing scripts,
trying to hack it together. now google listened and made it official. that's how you know it's
a real problem that needed solving. alright so here's what I want you to do. if you're studying
anything with math, try this with your notes. upload them to notebook LM, generate some flashcards,
generate a quiz, see how clean everything looks. now you can even export study sets and share
them with classmates. make your whole study group more effective. and listen, you can also repackage
this content. if you're a creator, take a 30-second clip showing the before and after of latex
rendering. post it on tiktok make a 60-second instagram reel with a split screen. create a youtube
short walking through one flashcard example. this update is visual. it's easy to show. and people
need to know about it. the reality is AI tools are getting better every single week. notebook
LM just made studying easier for millions of students. and if you're not keeping up with these
updates, you're falling behind. whether you're a student, a teacher, or someone building a business,
you need to know what's possible now. now if you want to take this even further and learn how
to use AI to actually scale your business, get more customers, and save hundreds of hours with
automation, you need to join my AI profit boardroom. ever want to make audio in different languages
with just one click? notebook LM just dropped something crazy. you can now make multiple audio
versions of your notes: different languages, different lengths, different tones, all from one
notebook. this is huge, and I'm going to show you exactly how to use it.
Google just changed everything with notebook LM. the mobile app got a massive update. the new
studio design is here. you can now create as many audio versions as you want from one notebook.
think about that: one notebook, 10 different audio versions, each one custom made for different
people. this wasn't possible before. now it is. here's what the new studio design does. you
can make multiple audio overviews from the same notebook. each one can be in a different language:
Spanish, French, German, Chinese, whatever you need. you can also change the length of each
audio. want a quick 2-minute summary? done need a deep 10-minute breakdown? easy and here's
the best part: you can customize the tone too. make it formal for business. make it casual for
friends. make it whatever fits your audience. this is all happening in the new studio design.
it's built right into the mobile app. you open your notebook, and boom, there's the studio.
you're a researcher. you have a paper in one notebook. make a formal audio overview for your
colleagues. make a simple audio overview for the general public. make audio overviews in 5 different
languages for international conferences. one notebook, 5 audio overviews, zero extra work. that's
what the studio design gives you. you're running a business. you have training materials in
a notebook. make a professional audio overview for new employees. make a casual audio overview
for team meetings. make short audio overviews for busy managers. make detailed audio overviews
for specialists. same notebook, different audio formats. everyone gets exactly what they need.
here's how you actually use the new studio design. open the notebook LM mobile app. go to your
notebook. you'll see the studio at the top. click it. now you'll see the option to create a
new audio overview. click that. pick your language from the drop-down menu. choose your length
for this audio overview: short, medium, long. then adjust the tone: formal, neutral, casual.
hit generate. wait about 30 seconds. done your first custom audio overview is ready. want to
make another audio overview from the same notebook? just repeat those steps in the studio: different
language, different length, different tone. make as many audio overviews as you want. they all
save in your studio. you can play them back anytime, share them with anyone, download them if
you need to. that's the power of multiple audio overviews per notebook. the speed of creating
multiple audio overviews is what gets me. 30 seconds per audio, that's all it takes. think about
recording audio yourself for each version. you'd need scripts, a microphone, editing software,
multiple takes for each version, fixing mistakes, processing each audio. that's hours of work.
the studio design does it in 30 seconds per audio overview, and each one sounds natural. no
robot voice, no weird pauses, just smooth professional audio overviews. and here's where the
studio design gets really good. the quality is consistent across all your audio overviews. every
audio sounds professional. no bad takes, no background noise, no stumbling over words. each
audio overview from the studio nails it every time. that's something you can't guarantee with
manual recording. even pros mess up sometimes. the studio doesn't. if you're serious about scaling
your business and saving hundreds of hours with AI automation like this studio design, you need
to check out my AI Profit Boardroom. it's the best place to learn how to get more customers
and automate everything with AI. we're using tools like this new Notebook LM Studio and dozens
of others to build real businesses, real results, no theory, just what actually works. let's
talk about the languages in the studio design. the studio supports a ton of them for your audio
overviews: English, Spanish, French, German, Italian, Portuguese, Chinese, Japanese, Korean,
and more keep getting added. this opens up global markets. with multiple audio overviews per
notebook, you're not stuck with just English anymore. you can reach people anywhere from one
notebook. the length customisation in the studio matters too. some people want quick summaries.
they're busy. they don't have time for long audio. the studio lets you give them a 3-minute
audio overview. other people want everything, every detail, every example. the studio lets you
give them a 15-minute audio overview. you serve both audiences from the same notebook with different audio overviews.
I've been testing the studio design with my team. we have training documents in notebooks. we
used to record training videos manually. that took days. now we put the documents in a notebook,
use the studio to generate multiple audio overviews, done in minutes. our team gets the same
quality training from different audio versions. we save 20 hours of work. that's 20 hours we
can spend on clients instead, all thanks to the studio design. here's a real use case for the
studio. you write a business proposal in a notebook. it's detailed, full of data. you need to
present it to two groups: the board of directors and the sales team. the board wants formal,
serious, data-focused. the sales team wants casual, energetic, action-focused. put your proposal
in a notebook. use the studio to make two audio overviews: one formal audio for the board, one
casual audio for sales. both groups get exactly what they need to hear from the same notebook.
the studio design also helps with accessibility through multiple audio overviews. not everyone
can read long documents. some people have visual impairments. some people have reading difficulties.
audio overviews from the studio make your notebook content accessible to everyone. and with
multiple languages in the studio, you're reaching people who don't speak your language. that's
inclusion through the studio design. the new studio interface is clean too. everything is organized.
you see all your audio overviews in one place. you can name them, tag them, search them. it's
not cluttered. it's not confusing. you know exactly what each audio overview is for. that matters
when you're managing multiple audio versions per notebook in the studio. and you're not sacrificing
quality with the studio. each audio overview sounds good: natural, professional. people won't
know it's AI generated unless you tell them. that means you can use these audio overviews from
the studio for client work, for products, for anything that needs to sound professional. the
best part is the studio design is live right now. you can start using multiple audio overviews
per notebook today. download the mobile app, open the studio, start creating. this is how you
get ahead while others are still doing things the old way. so here's what you do next. download
the notebook LM mobile app if you haven't already. create a notebook with some content you use
regularly. go to the new studio design. try making multiple audio overviews: different languages,
different lengths, different tones. see what works for your needs. experiment with the studio.
test different audio versions. find your workflow. then think about how you can integrate the
studio design into your business. where can multiple audio overviews save you time? where can
different languages expand your reach? where can custom tones improve your message? make a list.
start implementing the studio. this is how you get ahead. the people who win with AI are the
ones who move fast on updates like the studio design. they don't wait for perfect conditions.
they don't overthink it. they jump in and start using new features like multiple audio overviews
immediately. that's how you build an advantage. everyone else is still thinking about it. you're
already creating multiple audio versions in the studio. today I'm going to show you how Google's
notebook LM just became the most powerful free AI tool for content creators.
I'm talking about features that just dropped that nobody's using yet. you can turn any document
into professional videos, podcasts, study guides, and landing pages in minutes. this thing connects
to the web now. it finds sources for you automatically. and when you combine it with other free
tools, you get a content machine that runs on autopilot. this is going to change everything
about how you create content.
I just found a way to steal rankings from every competitor in your niche in under 10 minutes.
this new Google tool just got an insane update, and nobody is talking about it.
I'm about to show you how to turn any keyword into a full SEO strategy, plus a video that sells
itself. this is completely free, and it's going to change how you do content forever. watch
this. ok so here's what just happened.
Google just rolled out massive updates to notebook LM, and everyone missed the biggest part.
and they added video overviews, which means you can now turn your research into narrated videos
automatically. they upgraded the studio panel so you can save all your outputs in one place.
they added flashcards and quizzes, which is perfect for building FAQ schema. and here's the
crazy part: they connected it to Google Drive so you can pull in competitor pages and search
research instantly. but nobody is using this for SEO, and that's where the trick comes in.
I'm going to show you exactly how to use notebook LM to analyze the top 10 results for any keyword,
find the gaps they're all missing, and create content that ranks above them. then I'll show
you how to turn that same research into a video in 5 minutes. this is the fastest SEO workflow
I've ever used. notebook LM plus perplexity AI is insane. free notebook LM just changed everything.
you can now turn any document into a full podcast with real AI voices that sound 100% human.
and when you combine it with perplexity AI, you get a content machine that runs on autopilot.
this is the easiest way to create content in 2025. listen I'm about to show you something that's
going to blow your mind: two free AI tools that, when you combine them together, create the
most insane content workflow I've ever seen. first let's talk about notebook LM. this is a tool
from Google, and it's completely free. what it does is simple. you upload any document. could
be a PDF, could be a text file, could be a Google Doc, could even be a YouTube video link. and
notebook LM reads it. then it lets you do some crazy stuff with that content. the most insane
feature? the audio overview. this is where things get wild. you click one button, and notebook
LM turns your document into a full podcast with two AI hosts: one male voice, one female voice.
and they have a conversation about your content. they joke around. they ask each other questions.
they explain things in simple terms. it sounds so real that people think it's actual humans
talking. hey if we haven't met already, I'm the digital avatar of Julian Goldie, CEO of SEO
agency Goldie Agency. whilst he's helping clients get more leads and customers, I'm here to
help you get the latest AI updates. but wait, there's more. notebook LM doesn't just make podcasts.
it can also help you understand complex documents fast. let's say you have a 50-page report.
you don't have time to read all of it. you upload it to notebook LM. then you ask it questions:
what are the main points? what are the key takeaways? can you explain this section in simple
terms? and it gives you answers instantly. it's like having a personal assistant who's read
everything for you. you can also create study guides. you can create frequently asked questions.
you can create summaries. you can create briefing documents, all from one upload, all with one
tool, all for free. this alone is worth using. but now let me show you where the magic really
happens when you combine this with Perplexity AI. now if you don't know what Perplexity AI is, let me explain.
Perplexity is like Google, but way better. it's a search engine powered by AI. you ask it a
question, and instead of giving you 10 blue links, it gives you one perfect answer with sources,
with citations, with everything you need. the best part? it's connected to the internet in real
time, so it can find the newest information, the latest data, the most recent news. this is
huge because most AI tools are stuck in the past. they only know what happened up to their training
date. but Perplexity can search the web right now, today, this second, and give you the most
up-to-date information possible. so here's how you combine these two tools together, and this
is where things get really powerful. first you use Perplexity to research a topic. let's say
you want to create content about AI automation. you go to Perplexity, you type in "what are
the best AI automation tools in 2025," and Perplexity searches the entire internet. it reads
hundreds of articles. it finds the best information, and it gives you a clean summary with sources.
now here's the trick: you can tell Perplexity to write in a specific format. you can say, "write
this as a blog post," or you can with sources or write this as a research report or write this
as a step-by-step guide. and it will do exactly that in seconds, with perfect formatting, with
proper structure, with everything you need. now before I show you the rest of this workflow,
if you want to learn exactly how to use AI to scale your business and get more customers, you
need to check out the AI Profit Boardroom. this is my community where we share the latest AI
strategies that actually work, real case studies, real results. alright back to the workflow.
now let me tell you about some other ways you can use this. you can turn your old blog posts
into podcasts. if you've been blogging for years, you have tons of content sitting there. most
people will never read it, but they might listen to it. so take those old posts, run them through
notebook LM, turn them into audio. now you're repurposing content that you already created.
you're getting more mileage out of work you already did. you can turn books into podcasts. if
you've written a book, or if you have the rights to a book, you can upload chapters to notebook
LM, create audio summaries, create discussion episodes. this is perfect for book marketing.
people can listen to a summary before they buy, or they can listen to deep dives on specific
chapters. you can turn research into content. if you're in a technical field, you probably read
lots of research papers. most people don't have time for that, but you can take those papers,
upload them to notebook LM, create a podcast that explains the findings in simple terms. now
you're making complex information accessible. you're positioning yourself as an expert. you're
providing value to your audience. you can turn competitor content into your own insights. now
I'm not saying copy anyone, but you can use perplexity to research what your competitors are
doing. see what topics they're covering. see what's working for them. then you can create your
own unique take, your own perspective, your own content using the same workflow. research with
perplexity, create with notebook LM. now let me address something. some people might say this
is cheating. this is not real content creation. and to those people, I say you're wrong. you're
dead wrong. this is the smartest way to create content in 2025. everyone is using AI now. every
big creator, every big brand, every big company. if you're not using AI, you're falling behind.
you're wasting time. you're working harder than you need to. the goal is not to replace creativity.
the goal is to enhance it. the goal is to focus your time on the things that matter: strategy,
unique insights, personal stories, your own experiences. let me handle the research. let me
handle the formatting. let me handle the repetitive stuff. you focus on making it yours. you
focus on adding value. you focus on connecting with your audience. and here's the thing: your
audience doesn't care how you made the content. they care if it's valuable. they care if it
helps them. they care if it's entertaining. they care if it solves their problems. if you can
do that faster with AI, you should. if you can do that better with AI, you should. there's no
medal for doing things the hard way. so let me give you the exact step-by-step process. step
one: go to perplexity, research your topic, ask specific questions, get detailed answers. tell
it to format the response how you want it. step two: copy that content, go to notebook lm create
a new notebook, paste your content in or upload it as a file. step three: click on audio overview.
let it generate your podcast. this takes a few minutes. go get a coffee, come back, it's done.
step four: download the audio file. now you can upload it anywhere: youtube spotify your website,
social media, everywhere. step five: take that same content and repurpose it. create a blog
post, create social media posts, create email newsletters, create youtube video scripts. you're
getting 10 pieces of content from one research session. that's the power of this workflow. now
i want to talk about quality because some people think i a content is low quality, and they're
right if you use it wrong. if you just copy and paste without thinking, if you don't add your
own voice, if you don't add your own insights, then yeah, it's going to be garbage. but if you
use it as a starting point, if you use it as a research tool, if you use it to speed up your
process, then the quality is incredible. the notebook lm podcasts sound better than most real
podcasts. voices are clear, the pacing is good, the information is well structured. and because
you can customize the source material, you can make sure the content is exactly what you want.
you're in control. you're the director. ai is just the assistant. and with perplexity, the research
is better than what most people can do manually because it's searching thousands of sources.
it's reading hundreds of articles. it's finding the best information, and it's doing it in seconds.
you'd have to spend hours to do the same research manually, maybe days. this way, you get better
results faster. here's another pro tip: you can combine multiple sources in notebook lm you
don't have to use just one document. you can upload five documents, 10 documents, 20 documents,
and notebook lm will read all of them. it will find the connections. it will create a podcast
that ties everything together. this is perfect for creating comprehensive guides, or deep dive
episodes, or ultimate resource posts. now i want to show you one more advanced technique. you
can use perplexity to analyze trends. you can ask it what topics are trending in my niche right
now. what are people talking about on social media? what are the hot topics in the news? and
they will tell you. then you can create content about those trending topics using the same workflow:
research with perplexity, create with notebook lm and boom, you're riding the wave. you're getting
more views, more engagement, more growth. this is exactly what big media companies do. they
find trending topics, they create content fast, they publish it while people still care. and
now you can do the same thing. you don't need a team of writers. you don't need a team of producers.
you just need these two free tools and the knowledge of how to use them. let me tell you what
this means for the future. content creation is changing. the old way was slow, expensive, hard.
you had to write everything yourself. you have to record everything yourself. you have to edit
everything yourself. it took forever. most people gave up. but now, the barriers are gone. anyone
can create professional level content. anyone can compete with big brands. anyone can build
an audience. this is the democratization of media.
And if you want even more help with this, if you want to learn how to build a business around
AI, if you want to connect with other people doing the same thing, then you need to check out
the AI profit boardroom and if you want even more free resources inside, you'll get 50 plus
free AI tools and 200 plus chat GPT SEO prompts. you'll get access to 1000 plus free n8n workflows.
you'll get 200 plus chat GPT prompts. you'll see how one member made $10,000 plus with chat GPT.
You'll get a full blueprint to generate thousands of leads free with AI. plus you get a free
AI community, a free AI course, and proven AI case studies.
Today, I'm going to show you how Gemini and notebook LM create SEO content that ranks in under an hour.
I'm talking about content that used to take days. now it takes minutes with these two tools
working together. and the crazy part: notebook LM discover finds all your research sources automatically.
And Gemini canvas builds entire landing pages without touching code.
This is how we're scaling past eight figures at my agency, and I'm going to give you the exact
system, every single step, every single prompt.
So, here's what most people get wrong about AI content. they use one tool, they paste it into
WordPress, and they wonder why it doesn't rank.
The reason is simple: they're missing the research layer. they're missing the optimization layer.
they're missing the proof. the system I'm about to show you fixes all of that.
You're going to use two tools together: notebook LM for research, Gemini for creation. and when
these tools work together, magic happens. you get content backed by real sources, optimized
for search engines, with landing pages that convert, all in one workflow.
Hey, if we haven't met already, I'm the digital avatar of Julian Goldie, CEO of SEO agency Goldie agency.
Let me walk you through the system step by step with the actual prompts you need to copy and paste.
Step one is choosing your topic and finding keywords.
You need a target before you start. don't guess.
Go into Gemini and paste this prompt: list 10 short tail and long tail keyword ideas for [topic].
and then put your topic in brackets. prioritize search intent: transactional over informational
over navigational. show search questions, hit enter.
Gemini gives you a full keyword list with search intent mapped out and questions people are actually asking.
Pick your main keyword, pick four supporting keywords, write them down.
You'll use these throughout the entire process. Now, open notebook LM.
This is where the magic starts. notebook LM has this feature called discover. it automatically
finds the best sources on any topic.
No more clicking through 10 pages of Google results.
No more reading articles that don't help.
Discover does the work for you.
Here's the exact prompt: Create a research notebook about and then put your. [topic]. focus
on SEO intent, target keyword and then put your primary keyword and four supporting keywords.
Then write your four keywords. find authoritative sources, white papers, and blog posts.
But you're not done yet.
You need to actually pull in those sources. use the discover feature and paste this prompt:
discover top sources for and put your [topic].
Return up to 10 recommended articles, PDFs, and docs with a one line summary and a trust score from 1 to 10.
Add the best six to this notebook. notebook LM will scan the web, Find articles, rate them,
and add the best ones to your notebook.
This happens in like two minutes.
You just built a research library that would have taken hours manually.
If you want our team to help you scale this even further, We're offering free SEO strategy sessions.
and I mean actually free, no catch, no pressure.
We'll jump on a call with you and show you exactly how to use systems like this to grow your business.
We'll look at your specific situation, your niche, your competition.
And we'll map out a plan that works for you: real strategies, real tactics.
The same stuff we use with our paying clients. no pitch, no sales nonsense.
Just value. because we know if we help you get results, you'll remember us. the link is in the comments and description.
Now you have sources. next step is turning them into an outline.
This is where notebook LM really dominates.
It doesn't just store articles.
It reads them, synthesizes them, pulls out what matters.
Paste this prompt into into notebook LM: from the current notebook sources, create a research
brief summary, five most important facts, Seven frequently asked user questions, and a suggested
h1 plus seven h2 headings optimized for and then put your. [primary keyword].
Hit enter, wait 30 seconds.
You get a complete brief with facts pulled from multiple sources, with questions people actually
ask, with an SEO optimized outline. This is your blueprint.
Everything you need to write is right here.
Now, take that outline and go to Gemini. time to turn research into content. and here's the
exact prompt you need: Write a 1200 to 1500 word SEO article for and put your [primary keyword]
using this outline. and then paste your h1 and h2s. use conversational tone, include a 20 word
meta description, five key takeaways, and a short FAQ using the seven questions from the research
brief. use internal linking anchor suggestions and give three suggested CTAs.
Gemini pumps out a full draft in under a minute: a complete article with structure, with FAQs,
with meta description, with CTAs.
This is your first draft, and it's already better than most published content. but don't publish yet.
You need to add proof.
This is what separates content that ranks from content that disappears. go back to notebook
LM with this prompt: for the Gemini draft, attach inline citations for claims for each h2. add
one to two source quotes from this notebook with source links and timestamps or page numbers
if available. notebook LM maps your sources to your content. It adds citations. It adds quotes.
It shows exactly where each fact came from.
This builds trust, and trust gets you rankings.
Now, optimize for search engines.
Take your article back to Gemini and paste this prompt: Optimize the article for SEO.
Rewrite headings to include keywords where natural.
Create an optimized meta title under 60 characters.
Create schema.org JSON-LD for article with title, author, date, image, publisher. produce an
alt tag list for images and list 10 semantic keywords to target.
Gemini handles all the technical SEO work: schema markup, alt tags, semantic keywords, everything
Google wants to see. you don't need plugins.
You don't need an SEO expert.
Gemini does it all. but content needs more than text.
It needs visuals, social posts, thumbnails, and Gemini creates all of that.
Here's the prompt: generate five thumbnail headline options that are short, six social captions
for Twitter, six LinkedIn post captions, and a script for a 30 second video teaser. also output
three captioned screenshots suggestions for the article. one prompt, you get everything you
need to promote across every platform: headlines for YouTube, captions for social, screenshot ideas, all done.
Now, here's where it gets wild.
Gemini canvas, this tool builds actual working websites from prompts. no code, no developers,
just describe what you want. canvas builds it.
Paste this prompt into Gemini canvas: create a responsive single page landing site for this
article. include hero with h1, email capture form, three highlights from the article, and a
cta button. provide html, cs, j s. code, and a deployed share link or instructions to export.
make page fast and seo friendly. include meta tags, structured data, and server side rendered
content where possible. canvas generates the entire landing page.
You can see it live, edit it with more prompts, export the code, host it anywhere.
You just built a professional landing page in five minutes that would have cost hundreds of dollars.
But there's one more critical step: fact checking. you need to verify everything before you publish.
Go to notebook lm with this prompt: check the final article and landing page content against
notebook sources. flag any unsupported claims And suggest corrections. notebook lm scans your
content, compares it to your sources, catches mistakes, Suggests fixes. this protects your reputation
and keeps you honest. then do final polish in Gemini. polish the article for tone and readability.
Output final article, meta tags, social captions, and cta provide a short published checklist.
You now have everything: research backed by real sources, content optimized for seo landing
page ready to deploy, social posts ready to share, Citations that build authority, all created in under an hour.
Here's what you do Next pick one piece of content you need to create. follow this system start
to finish. use the exact prompts I gave you. time yourself. see how long it takes. my guess:
under an hour, Maybe 40 minutes. if you want our team to help you scale this even further, We're
offering free seo strategy sessions.
We'll show you exactly how to use systems like this to grow your business: real strategies,
No pitch, just value. the link is in the comments and description.
And if you're serious about ranking number one, they are in seo check out seo elite circle That's
where we share the exact systems We're using to scale past eight figures: real strategies, real results.
No fluff. link is in the description.
Go build something. use these prompts. test the workflow. then drop a comment and tell me how it went.
And i'll see you in the next one. new google notebook Lm update is insane. today I'm going to
show you how google just made notes turn into videos with crazy ai art. this thing is free.
it makes narrated slideshows from your messy docs. you get six wild art styles, and it takes
like one click. this is going to change how you make content forever. so google just dropped
this update to notebook lm, and it's honestly wild. they added something called video overviews
with nano banana visuals. yeah that's the real name, nano banana. i know it sounds like a fruit,
but it's actually google's image model that makes art from your notes. here's what happened.
notebook lm used to just make audio podcasts from your docs. now it makes full videos, narrated
videos with illustrations, with diagrams, with quotes pulled right from your source files. and
you don't need to be a designer. you don't need photoshop. you just upload your stuff and press
a button. hey if we haven't met already, i'm the digital avatar of julian goldie, ceo of seo
agency goldie agency. whilst he's helping clients get more leads and customers, i'm here to
help you get the latest ai updates. julian goldie reads every comment, so make sure you comment
below and let me know what you think. let me break down what this does. you throw in a pdf or
a google doc or even a youtube link. notebook lm reads it. then it generates a video overview.
that means a short slideshow with a. it's not robotic; it's actually pretty natural. now here's
where it gets crazy. you get six visual styles to pick from: watercolor, papercraft, anime,
whiteboard, retro print, and heritage. each one has a different vibe. watercolor looks soft
and artsy. papercraft looks like cut paper and crafts. anime is bold and colorful. whiteboard
is clean and simple. retro print looks like old posters. heritage looks classic and vintage.
you can switch styles instantly, no waiting, no rendering. you just click and boom, new art,
same narration, different look. this is huge because now you can match your brand or your audience
without learning design software. and there's two formats: brief and explainer. brief gives
you a quick recap. it's like 30 seconds to a minute, perfect for youtube shorts or tiktoks or
instagram reels. explainer is longer. it's structured. it goes deep. it's like 5 to 12 minutes.
that's perfect for full youtube videos or training content. before i move further, let me tell
you about two things that are going to change your business. first is my AI profit boardroom.
this is the best place to scale your business, get more customers, and save hundreds of hours
with AI automation. it's completely free. inside you get 50 plus free AI tools and 200 plus
chat gpt seo prompts. you get 1000 plus free n 8n workflows. you get a full blueprint to generate
AI case studies. both links are in the description. join now. all right, let's keep going. so
why does this matter? because most people hate turning notes into videos. it's boring. it takes
forever. you got to write a script. you got to find images. you got to record audio. you got
to edit. notebook lm does all of that in one shot. you upload your notes and get a finished
video in minutes. now let me tell you how to actually use this thing. first you open notebook
lm. it's free. you don't need to; you just need a google account. then you make a new notebook
or open one you already have. you add sources. that could be a pdf, a word doc, a google doc,
a web page, a youtube video, anything with text or info. once your sources are in, you hit the
video overview button. it's right there in the interface. then you pick your format, brief or
explainer. then you pick your style, one of those six nano banana styles i mentioned. then you
hit generate. that's it. you wait like a minute or two. you got a video. the video plays right
in the app. it's got narration. it's got slides. it's got visuals pulled from your sources.
if your pdf had a chart, it might show that chart. if your doc had a quote, it might highlight
that quote on screen. it's contextual. it's not random stock art. it's made from your actual
content. now here's where this gets insane for youtube creators. you can use the brief format
to pump out shorts. think about it. you got a long blog post. you throw it in notebook lm. you
generate a brief. you get a 30 second narrated video with cool visuals. you post it, done. you
just made a short in two minutes. or you use the explainer format for your main channel videos.
you got course notes. you got research. you got a bunch of pdfs. you throw them all in. you
generate an explainer. you get a five minute script with visuals. now you got a backbone for
your video. you can record over it. you can use the visuals as b-roll. you can even just re-record
the script in your own voice and use their slides and the visuals make great thumbnails. you
generate a video in the anime style. you screenshot one of the slides. you add some text, boom,
thumbnail. you didn't need canva. you didn't need a designer. notebook lm gave you the art.
so you pick the style that matches your vibe. that's the beauty of this. you're not locked into
one look. you can make the same video in six different styles and test which one performs better.
you can a b test your thumbnails. you can a b test your shorts. you can see what your audience
likes. now let me talk about how to actually export this stuff. when you generate a video overview,
it plays in the app. you can record your screen. you can use obs or quick time or whatever screen
recorder you got. you just hit record and play the video. now you got the file. or you can export
the frames. you can screenshot the slides. you can pull those images out and use them as b-roll.
you can drop them into premiere or final cut or cap cut. you can add your own voiceover. you
can add music. you can customize it however you want. the narration is generated by notebook
lm. it's ai voices. they sound like two people having a conversation. it's pretty natural. but
if you want to use your own voice, you just record over it. you use the script that notebook
lm wrote. you read it yourself. now it's your voice with their visuals. that's a killer combo.
now let me talk about the rollout because this isn't available everywhere right now. it's rolling
out on desktop first. it's in english first. google said they're expanding to more languages
and mobile soon. so if you're not seeing it yet, check back in a few days. it's coming. you
need a google account. you need to go to notebook lm. that's at notebooklm.google.com. it's
free. you don't need google one. you don't need to pay for anything. you just sign in and start
using it. now let me talk about the legal side. if you use notebook lm to make videos, make
sure you or have rights to the source material. don't throw in someone else's copyrighted pdf
and make a video from it. that's not cool. that could get you in trouble. use your own content.
use public domain content. use content you have permission to use. also if you're showing user
data or private info in your videos, blur it or anonymize it. don't show sensitive stuff. protect
people's privacy and check google's terms. if you plan to rehost or sell notebook lm content,
google might have rules about commercial use. read the terms. stay safe. all right, so here's
what you need to do right now. go to notebook lm. make a notebook. add some sources. generate
a video overview. try the brief format. try the explainer format. try all six styles. see what
works for you. then think about how you can use this. can you make shorts? can you make youtube
videos? can you make training videos? can you make a course? can you offer it as a service?
can you sell templates? pick one idea and run with it. this tool is free. this tool is powerful.
this tool just dropped. that means most people don't know about it yet. you got a head start.
use it. and if you want to go even deeper, join my ai profit boardroom. this is where we take
tools like notebook lm and build entire businesses around them. we automate everything. we scale
fast. the link is in the description. it's completely free. inside you get 50 plus free ai tools
and 200 plus chat gpt seo prompts. you get 1000 plus free n8n workflows. you get a full blueprint
to generate thousands of leads free with ai. plus you get a free ai community, a free ai course,
and proven ai case studies. both links are in the description. join now. all right, let's keep
going. comment below and tell me which nano banana style you're going to use. are you going
watercolor, papercraft, anime, whiteboard, retro print, or heritage? let me know. julian goldie
reads every comment, so make sure you drop one and stick around because i'm making a follow-up
video where i build a full course using just notebook lm outputs. no recording, no editing,
just notebook lm. that's coming soon. subscribe so you don't miss it. all right, see you in
the next one. these notebook lm hacks are insane. today i'm going to show you notebook lm hacks
that will blow your mind. these are brand new tricks that nobody's talking about yet. i'm going
to show you how to use notebook lm in ways google never intended. this stuff is so powerful.
it's basically unfair. by the end of this video, you'll be using ai like a total pro, and the
best part is completely free. all right, let's talk about notebook lm. this tool is crazy. most
people have no idea what it can actually do. they think it's just another ai chatbot. wrong
notebook lm is completely different from chat gpt or claude. it's better in a lot of ways, and
i'm going to show you exactly why. but first, let me explain what notebook lm actually is. it's
a tool made by google that lets you upload your own files. then it creates an ai that knows
everything about those files. you can upload pdfs, documents, websites, videos, audio files,
pretty much anything. then you can ask it questions about all that content. now here's what
makes notebook lm different. when you use chat gpt, is trained on general knowledge. it knows
a lot about everything, but it doesn't know anything specific about your business. notebook
lm is the opposite. you feed it your documents, then it becomes an expert on your stuff. hey
if we haven't met already, i'm the digital avatar of julian goldie, ceo of seo agency goldie
agency. whilst he's helping clients get more leads and customers, i'm here to help you get the
latest ai updates. i'm going to show you the real power moves, the hacks that actually matter,
the stuff that will save you hours every single day. let's start with hack number one. this
one alone is worth the entire video. you can turn any content into a. i don't mean a regular
podcast. i mean a full conversation between two people. they talk about your content like they're
on a radio show. they ask each other questions. they explain complex ideas in simple terms.
it sounds completely real. here's how you do it. upload your content to notebook lm. could be
a blog post, a pdf, a research paper, anything. then click on the audio overview button. that's
it. notebook lm will create a whole podcast episode about your content. two ai hosts talking
about your stuff. the crazy part is how good it sounds. these aren't robot voices. they sound
like real people having a real conversation. and here's another way to use this. let's say you
write a blog post. you spend hours on it, but most people won't read it. they're too busy. so
turn your blog posts into a podcast. upload it to notebook lm. generate the audio. now you have
a. put it on spotify. suddenly your written content reaches a whole new audience. hack number
two is about customizing those podcasts. most people don't know you can do this. you can actually
tell notebook lm what to focus on. let's say you upload a long document about marketing, but
you only care about the seo parts. you can tell notebook lm to focus on seo. then the podcast
will spend most of the time talking about that. here's how. before you generate the audio, look
for the customize button. it's right next to the audio overview button. click that. then type
in what you want the host to focus on. be specific. don't just say focus on the important parts.
say focus on the three main seo strategies discussed in this document. the more specific you
are, the better the results. you can also tell it to make the podcast shorter or longer. let's
say the default podcast is 20 minutes, but you only have a 10 minute drive. tell it to make
a 10 minute version. it will condense everything, focus on the most important points. now let's
talk about hack number three. this one is for people who work with teams. you can use notebook
lm as a shared knowledge base. here's the problem. most teams have someone creates a document,
they share it with the team, nobody reads it. then people keep asking the same questions over
and over. it wastes so much time. notebook lm solves this. upload all your company documents
to a notebook lm project. training materials, process docs, meeting notes, everything. then
share that project with your team. now anyone can ask questions and get instant answers. no
more searching through 50 different google docs. the ai knows everything, and it cites its sources.
all right, before i show you the next hack, i need to tell you something important. if you want
to actually scale your business with ai, you need to join the ai profit boardroom. this is where
i share all my best ai strategies. inside you'll get access to proven ai automations and a community
of entrepreneurs who are actually doing this stuff, not just talking about it. link is in the
description. now let's keep going. hack number four is about research. this is huge. if you're
a student or you create content, you can upload multiple sources to notebook lm. then ask it
to compare them or find contradictions or synthesize them into a single argument. you can also
use this for fact checking. let's say you find three or four other sources on the topic. upload
them all to notebook lm. ask if they all agree. now you know which information is reliable.
hack number five is for anyone who does interviews or podcasts. you can upload audio or video
files to notebook lm. then it transcribes them automatically, and you can ask questions about
the content. this is a game changer for repurposing content. let's say you do a one hour podcast
interview. upload the audio to notebook lm. then ask it for the 10 quotes or the main takeaways.
now you have content for social media, for email newsletters, for blog posts, all from one interview.
but here's where it gets really powerful. you can ask notebook lm to find specific moments in
the video. let's say you did a two-hour interview. you vaguely remember talking about email
marketing, but you don't remember when. just ask notebook lm when did we talk about email marketing.
it will tell you the exact time stamp. hack number six is about learning new skills. you can
use notebook lm as a personal tutor. upload a book or course materials. then ask it to quiz
you or explain concepts in different ways or give you examples. here's why this works so well.
most people learn by reading once and hoping it sticks. that's terrible for retention. you need
to engage with the material. ask questions. test yourself. notebook lm makes this easy. you
can also ask it to explain things like you're five years old or give you analogies. the ai will
adapt its explanation to match what you need. if you don't understand something, just keep asking
questions. hack number seven is for people who hate meetings. you can record meetings and upload
them to notebook lm. then ask it for action items or decisions that were made or who's responsible
for what. no more taking notes during meetings. just record it, upload it, ask the ai. i do
this for every client call. now after the call, i upload the recording, ask notebook lm what
the client wants, what we agreed to deliver, what the timeline is. then i send that summary
to my team. everyone knows exactly what to do, and i didn't have to spend 30 minutes writing
meeting notes. you can also use this to settle arguments. let's say two people remember a meeting differently. just
Just ask notebook lm what actually happened. it will tell you exactly what was said. hack number
eight is about combining notebook lm with other ai tools. this is where things get really powerful.
you can use notebook lm to research a topic, then copy that research into chat gpt or claude
and tell them to write something. here's another combo: use notebook lm to analyze customer
feedback. upload all your customer reviews, all your support tickets. ask it, what are the top
three complaints? what do customers love most? then take that information to chat gpt tell it
to write product updates or marketing copy. now everything you create is based on real customer
data. hack number nine is about organizing your ideas. you can upload random notes and thoughts
to notebook lm then ask it to organize them or find patterns or turn them into an outline. this
is perfect for people who have a million ideas but can't organize them. i keep a notes app on
my phone. whenever i have an idea, i write it down. but then i have hundreds of random notes.
now i upload them all to notebook lm ask it to group similar ideas together or find the best
ideas in the list. suddenly all those random thoughts become actionable. you can also use this
for brainstorming. let's say you're trying to come up with content ideas. you write down 20
random thoughts, upload them to notebook lm ask it which ideas have the most potential or how
you could combine ideas to create something better. hack number 10 is the most advanced one.
you can use notebook lm to create standard operating procedures. this is huge for business owners.
if you want to stay ahead with tools like notebook lm and automate more of your business with
ai you need to join the ai profit boardroom this. is where i share the exact systems and automations
we use to scale our agency. you'll learn how to use tools like notebook lm to organize your
research, automate your workflows, and save hundreds of hours. we've got members who are using
ai to cut their workload in half. if you want to scale your business, get more customers, and
save time with ai automation, the ai profit boardroom is the place to be. link is in the description.
and if you want the full process, sops and 100 plus ai use cases like this one, join the ai
success lab links. in the comments and description. you'll get all the video notes from there,
plus access to our community of 38,000 members who are crushing it with ai we share new use
cases every week. we break down every ai tool that matters, and we show you exactly how to use
them in your business. so if you want to stay ahead with ai join the ai success lab today. link
is below. that's it for today. hit the like and subscribe button, and i'll see you in the next one.